¬ Text file converted with loc_parser
{DRT_ROMAN_PROTECTORATE}				Accept that your independence is at an end, and become a client state, guaranteed safety by the armies of Rome. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ALLIANCE}					An alliance between us would cause our enemies to tremble in fear. 
{DRT_ROMAN_CEASEFIRE}					It is time to bring this needless bloodshed to an end. 
{DRT_ROMAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				It is time to end our alliance and for each to follow his own road to greatness! 
{DRT_ROMAN_TRADE}					Trade would bring wealth to both our peoples. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCESS}					The right to march Rome's armies across your lands would greatly aid us in defeating our enemies. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated. 
{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A recognition of our worth is always welcome. Our thanks. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold always eases the chance of misunderstanding before friendship is achieved. Our thanks. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is as gracious as it is sensible. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is gracious, but hardly sensible. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with little - that is to say, no - choice. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Bandying words is a pointless waste of breath at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			We have talked for a long time to little purpose, and yet decided nothing. This negotiation must come to an end. 
{DRT_ROMAN_REJECT_BRIBE}				Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods in a market, even for your gold. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Our freedom is precious, and not surrendered lightly. We see no need to become your servants - no matter how this is hidden behind fine words. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in our best interests at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				We see no need to end the fighting between our peoples just yet. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We can see no valid reason to end the alliance between our two peoples. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While you can see the need to march your soldiers through our lands, we do not. Permission must be refused at this time. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_REGION}				Our forefathers spent their lives to secure this land. Our blood has been spent to keep it. It is not our way to meekly hand over land to such as you!
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people would not be in our best interests and so we must, regretfully, reject your request. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what we expect or want. We decline your offer. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your daughters as Vestals or your wives as harlots, we would not bow to your demands.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for your gold.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			In all honour, we cannot accept your proposition, lest we be seen as thieves!
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			In all honour, we cannot accept your offer. We are willing to talk, not prostitute ourselves for a pittance.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your well-intentioned and magnanimous proposition. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our proposal is acceptable. 
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We propose the following...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel this proposal would more truly serve our interests...
{DRT_ROMAN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our good will could be secured, I'm sure, through a suitable golden gift...
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, Friend of Rome! What do you need to talk about?
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Ave! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_ROMAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			Make this quick! War leaves little time for niceties towards the likes of you!
{DRT_ROMAN_FINISHED}					This negotiation must end. May Jupiter Optimus Maximus bless our next meeting so that it is as useful as this one! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_PROTECTORATE}				The gods are on our side in this fight. You have nothing to gain from mighty Ares anymore - either become our subjects or be destroyed! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ALLIANCE}				Come, let us swear oaths of friendship and cause our foes to cower before us. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_CEASEFIRE}				Bloody Ares has had his fill of this war. The time has come for us to put an end to it. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			All friendships come to an end, and it is time for you to realise this too.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_TRADE}					Let us form a guest friendship to profit both our peoples.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCESS}					We would like you to grant us the right to pursue our foes through your lands.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ATTACK}					By Heracles, we would be grateful if you aided us against our enemies. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}					In Hades' name, you should know that it is better to pay us gold than to suffer our swords!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}					Our people could use one such as yourself, and are willing to prove it to you with gold.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}					Accept this gift as evidence of our goodwill to you and our reverence for Zeus.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}					It would be best for both our peoples to combine knowledge of our lands.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				This gift is very generous, and is to your honour as well as ours. We thank you. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Yes, your gold is acceptable. I shall take it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Yes, you were right to accept our proposal, and the gods will take note of your prudence. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			By the gods, you have made the wrong decision there! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		Well, that is that then.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			No - our people are not interested in this. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		Enough, by Zeus! Do your people not know when to shut their mouths?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_REJECT_BRIBE}				Ha, do you think that our people have no honour? We have more of it than that!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			By Ares, you will regret that insult! We shall not give up our freedom! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			Put aside your thoughts of alliance, for we shall not accept. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			Ha, a truce? We have no time for such nonsense as this, weakling! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				Friend, you must understand that we do not like the idea of letting any warriors of another realm enter our territories. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_REGION}				The barrows and tombs of our forefathers are here. Our blood has been spilled over this land. By the ancestors, we cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				No, we have no desire to attack these foes of yours, and fear that the gods would punish us for it. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				A threat? Ha! Do your worst, weakling! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				I am sorry, but my people cannot accept this gift from you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_OFFER}				By Hermes, we had hoped for better than this. We must reject your offer. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your entrails on the altars of the Olympian gods, we would not consider listening to such demands. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		No no, you offer too much, far too much. I fear the jealousy of the gods if our people accept!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			That is a good offer, and we are happy to accept.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal, though we hardly like the idea.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We offer...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_INFO}				We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After talking it over, we think this is better...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our friendship could be made certain, I'm sure, through a suitably large tribute - 'gift' would be a better word, perhaps - of gold...
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings, stranger! What do you have to say to us?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Get on with it. By Zeus, I can think of better things to do than listen to your whining, pig! 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_FINISHED}				This talk is over. Let us honour the gods and leave one another.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_PROTECTORATE}				It is time to accept that your independence is at an end, and become a client state protected by our mighty armies and cushioned by our wealth. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ALLIANCE}					An alliance between us could cause our enemies much fear, and this would be good. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to bring this profitless war to an end. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				It is time to end our profitless alliance...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_TRADE}					Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth, and in wealth lies greatness.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCESS}					Being allowed to march across your lands would greatly benefit us in our struggles against many enemies.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is always welcome, and reflects well upon the giver. Our gratitude for your kindness. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold can always ease any burden that friendship would impose. Our gratitude is almost boundless. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance is profitable to all, and a sign that wisdom has not died amongst your people. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your refusal is gracious, but perhaps ill-considered.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice but accept your decision.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Platitudes and empty words from such as you are pointless distractions at this time.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		Our ears grow weary of your endless chatter. Nothing worthy has been said. Good day.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_REJECT_BRIBE}				Our honour, loyalty and friendship are not cheap trinkets, to be purchased for a handful of coins. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Our freedom is precious, and not surrendered lightly. We see no need to become your servants - no matter how this is hidden behind fine words. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in our best interests at this time.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			We see no need to end the fighting between our peoples at the moment.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We can see cause why the alliance between us should come to an end.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ACCESS}				We cannot understand your need to march troops through our lands. This cannot happen. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_REGION}				This ground is ours, bought and paid for in the blood of many good and noble men. We will not grant dominion to you. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking these people be neither profitable or wise for us, so we must refuse your request. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_OFFER}				This offer is not what we expected. We refuse it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_DEMAND}				We cannot agree to this, even if you offered up your children and your children's children to our gods.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, not even for all the treasure you offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		A wise trader offers correct value: offer too much, and suspicions are raised. We must reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		A wise trader knows the value of what he seeks. Your valuation is cheap not wise, and we reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your magnanimous offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our generous proposal is welcome.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_OFFER}				We propose the following...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel this would be more profitable to all our interests...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Our friendship could be secured through a suitably large gift of gold...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend and ally! How can we help you?
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_CARTHAGE_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick, as our patience is not limitless, nor our kindness always guaranteed! 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_FINISHED}					This negotiation is over. May our next meeting be as fruitful...
{DRT_GREEK_PROTECTORATE}				It is time for you to bow the knee in supplication and accept us as your masters. You cannot resist our warriors' might. 
{DRT_GREEK_ALLIANCE}					Let us swear pious oaths and bind our realms together in alliance. 
{DRT_GREEK_CEASEFIRE}					The fighting has gone far enough. Let us swear to a truce. 
{DRT_GREEK_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				Our alliance is no longer appropriate. Let us look to our own interests once more. 
{DRT_GREEK_TRADE}					We are both wealthy, and are greatly renowned. We should form a guest friendship. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCESS}					Allowing us to march across your lands to attack our foes would be an act of true friendship. 
{DRT_GREEK_ATTACK}					Your assistance against our enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}					Honour us with this tribute, and we shall keep our swords sheathed.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset - just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both our realms.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_GIFT}					You do us much honour with this gift. Some god will take notice of your noble spirit. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Yes, gold helps men avoid misunderstandings. My thanks. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			You show wisdom and good sense in your acceptance. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			It is unfortunate that you should reject our proposal.
{DRT_GREEK_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			We have no interest in your proposal. We must refuse. 
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			Enough - you would weary the mountains of Arcadia with your persistance. 
{DRT_GREEK_REJECT_BRIBE}				Do you not know that we have a sense of honour? You would offend the gods with your shameless talk! 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			By Zeus Eleutherius, we shall not give up our freedom to such as you! We shall prove our worth to you with our swords. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				I am afraid that we are not seeking an alliance right now. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				We do not see any reason to agree to a truce with your realm. We shall resolve our dispute on the battlefield. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				Our oaths of alliance are sacred to the gods, and we do not wish to offend them by abandoning our pact. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ACCESS}				Unfortunately it is not a matter of policy to allow others to march into our territory. We fear Hecate's disapproval. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_REGION}				Our forefathers' blood watered the ground here. Our people have worked these fields. We cannot meekly hand over any part of our land to you! 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_ATTACK}				We may anger some god if we were to attack this realm. We have no interest in it, and so we must refuse.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your threats are futile and empty. Take care in the future to mind your own interests alone.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what we wanted. We refuse to agree to your scheme. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_DEMAND}				We shall not bow the knee to your demands. Be careful, lest you offend the gods with your behaviour. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up land, not even - perhaps especially - for gold. 
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			You offer too much, and in good conscience we cannot accept.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Your offer is neither fair nor reasonable. We cannot accept something so paltry.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}				This is a good offer, by Zeus. We accept. 
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to our proposal is reasonable and will please the gods. Our thanks.  
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal, but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_OFFER}				We suggest the following...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We ask for the following...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your proposal, we feel the following would be to our benefit... 
{DRT_GREEK_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Anyone who wished to demonstrate true friendship could always offer a suitable gift of gold...
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, noble ally! How may we help you?
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Well met, stranger. What did you wish to discuss?
{DRT_GREEK_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			It is fortunate that heralds are protected by Hermes. Otherwise, you would feel the edges of our swords. 
{DRT_GREEK_FINISHED}					Here ends the discussion. Let us close with libations to the gods, and be on our way.
{DRT_EGYPT_PROTECTORATE}				Pharaoh - health and strength to him - states: "All Your Base Are Belong To Us!" It is time to become a client kingdom under kindly rule of Pharaoh. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ALLIANCE}					An alliance may cause Pharaoh's enemies to tremble in fear. This would be a fine thing. 
{DRT_EGYPT_CEASEFIRE}					Pharaoh considers that the time is right to end the bloodshed that taints our relationship. 
{DRT_EGYPT_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				Pharaoh - health and strength to Him! - feels that it is time to end the alliance with you. 
{DRT_EGYPT_TRADE}					Pharaoh recognises that trade would do much to bring wealth to his servants and children. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCESS}					Pharaoh considers that asking permission to march across your territory before he exercises his divine right to do so avoids confusion and makes you feel better. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ATTACK}					Your humble assistance against the great Pharaoh's enemies would be greatly appreciated.
{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is a blessing to the giver. May Pharaoh's thanks warm your souls. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold can often aid in easing misunderstanding between those who would be friends. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			Your acceptance is as gracious as it is wise.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is not gracious, and likely to cause much offence to our noble Pharaoh. 
{DRT_EGYPT_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left Pharaoh with no choice in this matter.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			Bandying empty words with such as you is a pointless distraction from the proper business of state.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}			Many words have been spoken, and have blown away as on the desert wind. Nothing worthy of Pharaoh's attention has been spoken and this negotiation is ended.
{DRT_EGYPT_REJECT_BRIBE}				Pharaoh's honour and friendship are not for sale, particularly for such a derisory sum in gold. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			Pharaoh's rule is precious, and not surrendered lightly. He sees no need to become your servant - no matter how this is concealed by smooth words. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				An alliance would not be in Pharaoh's interest at this time.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				The wise and belligerent Pharaoh sees no reason to stop fighting just yet.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				The wise and faithful Pharaoh sees no excuse to dishonour himself and his friends by denying that a mutual friendship continues to exist. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ACCESS}				While you may see a reason to march your troops through Pharaoh's lands, he does not. Permission is refused. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_REGION}				All that is good is here, all that our forefathers' worked to achieve. Pharaoh cannot, in all conscience, hand over a land held in sacred trust from the Gods.  
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_ATTACK}				In what way would the peace-loving and kindly Pharaoh profit from such an attack? Your request is objectionable.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not what Pharaoh expects from supplicants, and it is declined.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_DEMAND}				Even if you offered up your children as slaves to the greater glory of Pharaoh, he would not consider bowing to your demands.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, even for inadequate amounts of gold.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}			Pharaoh - health and strength be his - wonders if you understand the process of negotiation. Your offer is so embarrassingly high that we cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Pharaoh - life, wisdom and glory unto him - would consider your offer too worthless to be worthy of acceptance.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}				The magnanimous Pharaoh has smiled upon your well-crafted proposal.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Your response to Pharaoh's proposal is acceptable, if a little tardy...
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_OFFER}				In the name of Pharaoh, we propose the following...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_DEMAND}				In the name of Pharaoh, we suggest the following compromise...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_INFO}				In the name of Pharaoh, we trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After due consideration the mighty Pharaoh feels this would more truly serve his interests...
{DRT_EGYPT_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Pharaoh's friendship would be facilitated by a suitably large tribute in gold. Perhaps, on reflection, it might be better to term it a gift. Yes, gift...
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome, friend of the great Pharaoh! What aid do you require?
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}			Greetings from the noble and magnificent Pharaoh. What proposal or do you wish to lay, most humbly, before him?
{DRT_EGYPT_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}			Be speedy, for Pharaoh's servants have many matter of state that take precedence over such as you. 
{DRT_EGYPT_FINISHED}					This negotiation must now end. May the next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_EASTERN_PROTECTORATE}				You have fought well, but you are no match for our warriors' arms. It is time for you to bow to us as suppliants.
{DRT_EASTERN_ALLIANCE}					In truth, an alliance between us would bring fear to the hearts of all our enemies.
{DRT_EASTERN_CEASEFIRE}					We have struggled enough, and only cruel Ares has seen any profit. Let us end the fighting. 
{DRT_EASTERN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}				Let us renounce our oaths of alliance and look to our own interests, making propitious sacrifices to the gods. 
{DRT_EASTERN_TRADE}					Let us form a guest friendship to benefit our peoples with honour and prosperity.  
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCESS}					We ask for the right to march our armies through your territory, so that we may strike down our foes from an unexpected direction. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ATTACK}					We would greatly honour you if you were to add your warriors to our struggle against our foes. 
{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}					Pay us a suitable tribute, and we promise not to bring war to your lands.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				We thank you for this gift. It is testimony to your noble spirit and integrity. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Ah, gold... Just what I had in mind. I thank you.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}			The gods will rejoice at your gracious acceptance.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}			Your rejection is imprudent, but graciously done. 
{DRT_EASTERN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}			You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}			No, we are not interested. Perhaps you could find someone else who is? 
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		It seems like your talking has gone on longer than the labours of Heracles! It is time for you to put an end to your speeches.
{DRT_EASTERN_REJECT_BRIBE}				Do you think that my honour is for sale for such a pitiful amount of gold? Why, you would need to offer me all the wealth of Midas before I gave it up! 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}			We surrender our independence to no man. Why should we become slaves? For the sake of a few fine words? We think not! 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}				We both have great power and renown. Let us combine our strength in an alliance, and delight the immortal gods.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}				There is no need for a truce at the moment. The vengeful gods still desire your punishment.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}				We see little need to end such a profitable and benign relationship. The alliance between us is a bulwark against jealous rivals! 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ACCESS}				Although you see good reasons to march your armies hither and thither through our lands, we do not. We must turn down your request.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_REGION}				Our dead lie in this ground. Our cities cover the land. Our farmers work the earth. We see no good reason to give up even the smallest part of our possessions!
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_ATTACK}				Attacking this realm is not something that we could undertake lightly, so we must refuse to carry out your wishes for now. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Our power is quite sufficient to counter your vain and idle threats.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_OFFER}				This proposal is not appropriate. We decline your offer.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_DEMAND}				We will not bow to your demands. Conqueror's justice is no justice at all, and this would be the first step along that road. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}			We cannot give up our lands, not even for gold. Not even for that much gold. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your foolish generosity deceives no one! What are you up to? We reject your offer!
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}			Your insulting parsimony would anger the gods. Why do you not make a sensible offer? We reject this proposal.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your offer. Let us swear solemn oaths and both profit from this agreement.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}				Yes, we can accept this. May the gods defend our agreement.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				We accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_OFFER}				We offer the following...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_DEMAND}				We demand the following...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_INFO}				We trust you will find this information useful...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After considering your last offer, we feel this arrangement would be more equitable...
{DRT_EASTERN_COUNTER_BRIBE}				Friendship can be encouraged with gold, if this is offered in suitable quantities...
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}			Welcome unto you, noble and generous ally! What help do you need? 
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings, esteemed one! What do you wish to propose?
{DRT_EASTERN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		You had better be quick with your proposals, before the avenging Furies discover your presence here and come to punish you!
{DRT_EASTERN_FINISHED}					These talks are ended. Let us sacrifice to the gods and pray Zeus that our next meeting be as valuable.


¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 22/03/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************


¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 21/04/2004 17:30:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 13/05/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_BARBARIAN_PROTECTORATE}				The gods are on our side in this fight. You have nothing to gain from mighty Ares anymore - either become our subjects or be destroyed! 
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_THREAT}				A threat? Ha! By Nemesis, our warriors will make you regret those words!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_GIFT}				We shall not accept what we do not understand. We are suspicious of such inexplicable gifts.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_THREAT}				By Zeus, your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_THREAT}				By Zeus, your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_GIFT}				If we were to accept this gift, we would become indebted to you. We do not understand your motives, so we cannot accept.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				We accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_THREAT}				Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				we accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_THREAT}				By Apollo, try threatening someone weaker than yourself. As it is, we laugh at your threats!
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_GIFT}				I fear Greeks, even when bearing gifts. Indeed, I fear any kingdom that makes such mysterious offers, and so I must refuse.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We accept your proposal but we dont have to like it.

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/06/2004 16:48:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.
{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}					We promise that we will not attack you for the right price.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}					A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}					Please accept this gift from us to show that we are genuine. 
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}					Combining our knowledge of the world will benefit both parties.

{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				Although your proposal is lacking in merit, we must accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We must accept this insulting proposal as, at heart, we are realists first and foremost.
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				You think to insult Pharaoh with this proposal, but for the good of His people He will ignore your crudity.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We must accept your proposal, although it pains us to do so.
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}				We must accept this insulting proposal as, at heart, we are realists first and foremost.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Although your proposal profits us little, we must accept it.

{DRT_EGYPT_PROTECTORATE}				Pharaoh - health and strength to him - states: "All Your Base Are Belong To Us!" It is time to become a client kingdom under the kindly rule of Pharaoh. 

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 17/06/2004 13:01:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*		This particular divider does not denote a changes round.
¬*	This is when the files were locked to be sent for Russian and Polish translation.
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 07/07/2004 17:15:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	While your offer of territory is generous, we do not think we would keep it for long before your armies marched in and so we reject it. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	What is given can soon be taken away! We must reject your offer of access, as you may simply revoke it and leave our armies stranded. 
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	We are not fools. If we granted you marching rights, you would not march on your enemies. Our lands would be prey to your ambitions!
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	We do not wish you to attack our rivals. We have no faith that your soldiers would ever see a battlefield and less faith that your promises are worthwhile.
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Your words promise peace, but your actions have not always been those of peaceful men. Your promise not to attack us cannot be trusted, and we reject this offer.
{DRT_ROMAN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	We will not take your gold. We have no faith that we would ever see the money you promise so glibly. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	You offer us more lands and peoples to rule? Some may be fooled by this, but we see it for the trick that it is - you wish to spread out our forces, and then attack us when we are weak!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	Bah, your promises are worth nothing. Like Aeetes, you would welcome our armies into your lands and then turn on them when they could not escape!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	We know you as dishonest and guileful, like Prometheus, and we have no intention to give you a chance to march your warriors into our lands!
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	We can handle our own foes well enough! We certainly do not require the 'help' that treacherous rogues such as you might offer.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	We would listen to this if it came from an upright and genuine man, but we trust you no more than we would trust Typhoeus or the Hydra.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Our honour and strength is worth more than your false gold, and we shall not be tricked by such obvious ploys. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	We cannot accept lands from you. The risk is too great and we would not profit by it. If we take your gift, your soldiers will only snatch it back!
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	We would not profit by marching armies through your land. You would only change your minds afterwards. We reject this proposal.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	We cannot give you the right to march through our lands. You may - it is true - be entirely honourable, but your history weighs heavily against you...
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	Your offer to attack our rivals may be sincere, but we prefer to think otherwise. We reject your offer as profitless and too risky to believe.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Too often in the past you have promised peace and then settled matters with the sword. Maybe there is profit in believing you will not attack, but we reject your offer.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Your words promise gold, but the glitter of your gold cannot blind us to the swords in your hands. We must reject your offer of tribute for our own safety.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	No, no, we do not wish to be burdened with the rule over these lands. By Hecate, you just want to offload your problems onto us.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	You make a generous offer, but we know how you are as cunning and malicious as the Sphinx. You may just wish to draw our warriors into a trap, just like Ares in the jar!
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	If Jason had known of Medea's poisonous character, he would not have welcomed her into his home. We know your character, and so we shall not welcome you into ours.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	There is no need for you to involve yourselves in our affairs. We would only expect treachery worthy of the Telchines! 
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	We are no fools, and realise that you intend to wage war on us all the same, just like the insatiable Titans.
{DRT_GREEK_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Gold is a fine, shining metal, yet we are not blinded by it like Phrygians. Gold is only as worthy as the intentions behind it, and yours are false.
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	Pharaoh rejects your offer of new lands to rule. When such as you cast a thing aside, it is hardly worthy! Besides, He believes that, in time, you would dishonourably snatch back your gift!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	Pharaoh has no interest in marching his armies through your lands. After all, you may change your minds and attack His servants once they are far from home!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	Pharaoh does not wish His lands to be polluted by your armies, and your request is denied. After all, you cannot be trusted to march through without attacking!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	Pharaoh does not need the aid of such as you in attacking his rivals and foes. Although you may promise much, the past shows that you achieve little!
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Pharaoh is not a fool, so why do you try to deceive him with false peace? Your word is known to be as worthless as the desert dust, so He must reject your hollow promises.
{DRT_EGYPT_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Pharaoh does not need your gold. The tribute of the worthless is, of itself, worthless in His sight. Pharaoh thusly spurns your offer.
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}	We have no desire to rule over these lands! Why, it would be a greater burden than Atlas', and you know it well!
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}	Why should we want to send our warriors into your territory? It would only give you an excuse to double-cross us!
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}	No, this is foolishness. Does a man welcome a lion into his home? Of course not. Neither shall we welcome your swords into our kingdom!
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}	We doubt your sincerity here. Like Autolycus, you spin webs of deceit and trickery, and are simply trying to manipulate us. 
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}	Peace on your terms? I think not. In the past you and your people have been devoted followers of bloody Ares, and we see no reason to trust you now.
{DRT_EASTERN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}	Do you think that all Phrygians are so greedy for gold? We have wits too, and shall not accept your dishonest overtures.

{DRT_ROMAN_THREAT}				Roman wrath can be turned aside, providing that you are sufficiently respectful - and can afford the price...
{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_ROMAN_GIFT}				Accept this gift as a mark of our admiration for your virtue and courage. 
{DRT_ROMAN_INFO}				If we share our knowledge of the world we will all benefit. 

{DRT_BARBARIAN_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_GIFT}				Friend, please accept this honourable gift from noble men.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_INFO}				From the forest and mountains of the North to the rocky islands of the South, let us share our knowledge of the Earth.

{DRT_CARTHAGE_THREAT}				Gold is always preferable to blood. For a price our armies will not march against you. 
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_GIFT}				Accept this gift as more than a token of our good will. It is in an investment in our future as friends!
{DRT_CARTHAGE_INFO}				Combining our knowledge of the world will profit both of us.

{DRT_EGYPT_THREAT}				Pharaoh's mighty wrath is not cheaply turned aside! His mighty armies will not attack, but only for the right price.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_GIFT}				Pharaoh is pleased to offer even unworthy mortals such as yourselves gifts and trinkets as signs of his good will. 
{DRT_EGYPT_INFO}				Pharaoh's knowledge is boundless, but combining it with your paltry knowledge of the world will surely benefit us all.

{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}				The spears of our kingdom are poised to strike at you - but you may yet save yourselves...
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_GIFT}				You have great honour and renown. Receive this gift, a sign that we too are noble men.
{DRT_EASTERN_INFO}				Even as Earth is surrounded by Ocean, let us share our knowledge of the world.

{DRT_GREEK_THREAT}				You will do as we say, if you wish to ward off the bloody deeds of Ares!
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}				PLACEHOLDER A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_GREEK_GIFT}				We consider you a great friend. Please accept this gift as a mark of honour.
{DRT_GREEK_INFO}				Let us share our knowledge of the Earth, so that we may see it as clearly as Helius does.


{DRT_ROMAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Although your proposal is lacking in merit, honour and virtue, we must accept it.
{DRT_EASTERN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		By Tartarus, do not think that we are happy to accept this shameful demand!
{DRT_EGYPT_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Pharaoh will rise above your slurs on His honour and accept this crude and insulting proposal, but only for the good of His people.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Gods! To accept this demand leaves a bitter taste in our mouths, but we shall go along with it - for now...
{DRT_GREEK_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			We must agree to this - for now. But we pray that the Furies give you your just reward for your insult!
{DRT_CARTHAGE_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Your proposal has little profit in it, and less to like. Even so, we must accept your offer. 

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 15/07/2004 17:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 22/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 29/07/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 05/08/2004 12:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 12/08/2004 09:53:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 19/08/2004 16:05:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_EASTERN_THREAT}	There may be enough gold in your coffers to turn aside our armies. You must consider the value of your lives and freedom...

{DRT_ROMAN_DECLINE_OFFER}	This offer cannot be matched. We must decline your offer. 
{DRT_BARBARIAN_DECLINE_OFFER}	No. We shall not agree to this offer.  
{DRT_CARTHAGE_DECLINE_OFFER}	We cannot meet this offer and therefore must refuse it.
{DRT_GREEK_DECLINE_OFFER}	Sadly we cannot accept this proposal. 
{DRT_EGYPT_DECLINE_OFFER}	This proposal is beyond our means, we must regretfully decline.
{DRT_EASTERN_DECLINE_OFFER}	Sorry, but I am afraid that this proposal is not for us.

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 01/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THIS FILE GONE FOR LOCALISATION!!!
¬*		ALL CHANGES & ADDITIONS MADE POST THE DATE SPECIFIED 
¬*			BELOW MUST GO UNDERNEATH THIS DIVIDER!!!
¬*
¬*
¬***** Changes made after 03/09/2004 09:00:00
¬*
¬****************************************************************************************
¬****************************************************************************************

{DRT_ROMAN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_BARBARIAN_BRIBE}				Our people would value your qualities, friend. How much value... well, you tell us.
{DRT_CARTHAGE_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EGYPT_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_EASTERN_BRIBE}				You would be very valued in our kingdom, sir. But you may tell us how much you would like to be valued.
{DRT_GREEK_BRIBE}				We would value your services greatly, by Hades, and we are willing to prove it.


¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			EXPANSION PACK TEXT BEGINS HERE!!!
¬*		ALL TEXT BELOW THIS LINE SHOULD BE EXPANSION ADDITIONS/CHANGES ONLY!!!
¬*
¬*¬***** Changes made after 05/01/2005 15:18:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


¬ Typo corrected	
{DRT_BARBARIAN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}		It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 

¬ Hun and Nomad variants	

{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_BRIBE}				Gold always smooths the path to understanding between those who would be friends. Many thanks.
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_COUNTER}			Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}			Sometimes the strong warrior must bite his tongue and accept the unacceptable. We agree to your proposal, for now...
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_GIFT}				A gift is a measure of the giver. Our thanks. 
{DRT_HUN_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}			We accept your well-intentioned and generous offer.
{DRT_HUN_ACCESS}				The right to pursue our enemies across your lands would greatly help us.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance shows wisdom.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_HUN_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}		Your rejection is poorly considered, and could be taken as an insult by some. 
{DRT_HUN_ALLIANCE}				An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_HUN_ATTACK}				Your assistance against our enemies would earn our goodwill.
{DRT_HUN_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_HUN_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_BRIBE}			Our friendship could be made certain through a suitably large tribute - perhaps 'gift' would be a better word - of gold...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_INFO}				We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_OFFER}			We offer...
{DRT_HUN_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}			After mulling over your proposal we think that this is better...
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ACCESS}			While you can see the need to send your warriors through our lands, we cannot. We must refuse, in case others think we are simpletons.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			An alliance would not be a good thing. We have spoken, and will not change our minds. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_ATTACK}			We cannot see how an attack on these people would help us. We must reject your demand. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			End the fighting! This is a good joke! We see no need to end any fighting. Some of you yet live!
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_DEMAND}			Even if you offered up your entrails on the altars of our highest gods, we would not consider listening to such demands. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_GIFT}				Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_NULLIFY}			We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_OFFER}			We having nothing to offer in return, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your offer is generous, very generous - and for that reason we must turn it down. The sharpest sword can be hidden beneath a pile of gold…
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}		Freedom is a precious thing, and not given up lightly. You do not need us as your servants and slaves. Your fine words are just that - words on the wind.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_REGION}			Our blood has been spilled over this land. Our dead lie here. We have bought this land with lives. We cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_THREAT}			Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_HUN_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}		We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}		Only trusting fools would grant you the right to send armies across their lands. We are not trusting fools. You may not pass!
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}		Your words are worthless! In one breath you will give the right to pass across your lands, and with the next deny that any such words were spoken. Perhaps you look for an excuse for war…
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}		Your word cannot be trusted. You say that you will attack our foes, but only a witless idiot would listen and believe such a thing...
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}		Your words would be welcome from honest warriors, but too often you have said one thing and done another. We must reject your promise.
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}		You offer us land, but we do not believe that it would be ours for long! Before the foals are born, your armies will have snatched it back. We reject your offer!
{DRT_HUN_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}		We will not take your gold. It is tainted with lies and false friendship, a gift made by ill-speaking liars to fools - and we are not fools! 
{DRT_HUN_FINISHED}				This talk is over. May our next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_HUN_GIFT}					Accept this gift in a spirit of warrior brotherhood! Let us never draw swords against one another! 
{DRT_HUN_INFO}					Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world!
{DRT_HUN_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 
{DRT_HUN_PROTECTORATE}			Accept that your time of freedom is now over. You will live long and prosper under our protection. 
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick. There are better things to do today than listen to your pathetic mewling! 
{DRT_HUN_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}		Greetings! What did you wish to offer us today?
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_BRIBE}				We are not simple-minded. Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods for sale in a market. No, not even for your gold. 
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}		Bandying empty words with such as you is a waste of time just now. 
{DRT_HUN_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}		We have done you the honour of listening to your tripe, and yet nothing has been said here that was worth the hearing. This babbling is over.
{DRT_HUN_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_HUN_TRADE}				Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth to all of us.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_BRIBE}			Gold always smooths the path to understanding between those who would be friends. Many thanks.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_COUNTER}			Your answer is acceptable.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_DECLARATION}		Sometimes the strong warrior must bite his tongue and accept the unacceptable. We agree to your proposal, for now...
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_GIFT}			A gift is a measure of the giver. Our thanks. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCEPT_PROPOSITION}		We accept your well-intentioned and generous offer.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACCESS}				The right to pursue our enemies across your lands would greatly help us.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_ACCEPTANCE}		Your acceptance shows wisdom.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_DECLARATION}		You have left us with no choice.
{DRT_NOMAD_ACKNOWLEDGE_REJECTION}		Your rejection is poorly considered, and could be taken as an insult by some. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ALLIANCE}				An alliance between us would cause all our enemies to tremble in terror. 
{DRT_NOMAD_ATTACK}				Your assistance against our enemies would earn our goodwill.
{DRT_NOMAD_BRIBE}				A man such as yourself would prove to be a valuable asset, just how much value is up to you.
{DRT_NOMAD_CEASEFIRE}				It is time to end the bloodshed. 
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_BRIBE}			Our friendship could be made certain through a suitably large tribute - perhaps 'gift' would be a better word - of gold...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_DEMAND}			We suggest the following...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_INFO}			We hope you will find this useful...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_OFFER}			We offer...
{DRT_NOMAD_COUNTER_PROPOSITION}		After mulling over your proposal we think that this is better...
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ACCESS}			While you can see the need to send your warriors through our lands, we cannot. We must refuse, in case others think we are simpletons.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ALLIANCE}			An alliance would not be a good thing. We have spoken, and will not change our minds. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_ATTACK}			We cannot see how an attack on these people would help us. We must reject your demand. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_CEASEFIRE}			End the fighting! This is a good joke! We see no need to end any fighting. Some of you yet live!
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_DEMAND}			Even if you offered up your entrails on the altars of our highest gods, we would not consider listening to such demands. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_GIFT}			Your motives for this gift remain a mystery. We cannot accept it.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_NULLIFY}			We do not agree. We can see no excuse that would mean the end of our alliance. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_OFFER}			We having nothing to offer in return, and we must turn you down. 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_HIGH}		Your offer is generous, very generous - and for that reason we must turn it down. The sharpest sword can be hidden beneath a pile of gold…
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PAYMENT_TOO_LOW}		You must take us for simple-minded fools who cannot count. We cannot accept such paltry terms.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_PROTECTORATE}		Freedom is a precious thing, and not given up lightly. You do not need us as your servants and slaves. Your fine words are just that - words on the wind.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_REGION}			Our blood has been spilled over this land. Our dead lie here. We have bought this land with lives. We cannot give you any part of our birthright! 
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_THREAT}			Your empty threats do not worry us. We will take our chances.
{DRT_NOMAD_DECLINE_YEARLY_PAYMENT}		We cannot give up our lands, even for such trinkets.
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ACCESS_DEMAND}		Only trusting fools would grant you the right to send armies across their lands. We are not trusting fools. You may not pass!
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ACCESS_OFFER}		Your words are worthless! In one breath you will give the right to pass across your lands, and with the next deny that any such words were spoken. Perhaps you look for an excuse for war…
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ATTACK_OFFER}		Your word cannot be trusted. You say that you will attack our foes, but only a witless idiot would listen and believe such a thing...
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_ATTACK_THREAT}		Your words would be welcome from honest warriors, but too often you have said one thing and done another. We must reject your promise.
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_REGION_OFFER}		You offer us land, but we do not believe that it would be ours for long! Before the foals are born, your armies will have snatched it back. We reject your offer!
{DRT_NOMAD_DISHONEST_TRIBUTE_OFFER}		We will not take your gold. It is tainted with lies and false friendship, a gift made by ill-speaking liars to fools - and we are not fools! 
{DRT_NOMAD_FINISHED}				This talk is over. May our next meeting be as useful...
{DRT_NOMAD_GIFT}				Accept this gift in a spirit of warrior brotherhood! Let us never draw swords against one another! 
{DRT_NOMAD_INFO}				Wisdom shared is wisdom gained, so let us share what we know of the world!
{DRT_NOMAD_NULLIFY_ALLIANCE}			It is time to be honest and plain. Let us put aside words of friendship such as "alliance" and go our separate ways. 
{DRT_NOMAD_PROTECTORATE}			Accept that your time of freedom is now over. You will live long and prosper under our protection. 
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_ALLIED}		Welcome friend! How can we help you?
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_AT_WAR}		Be quick. There are better things to do today than listen to your pathetic mewling! 
{DRT_NOMAD_RECIPIENT_WELCOME_NEUTRAL}	Greetings! What did you wish to offer us today?
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_BRIBE}			We are not simple-minded. Our honour and friendship are not cheap goods for sale in a market. No, not even for your gold. 
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_NOT_INTERESTED}		Bandying empty words with such as you is a waste of time just now. 
{DRT_NOMAD_REJECT_TOO_MANY_COUNTERS}	We have done you the honour of listening to your tripe, and yet nothing has been said here that was worth the hearing. This babbling is over.
{DRT_NOMAD_THREAT}				Our swords can always be turned aside by gold. But can your peace and life be valued too highly?
{DRT_NOMAD_TRADE}				Trade between our peoples would bring much wealth to all of us.

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 18/04/2005 12:45:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 27/06/2005 11:50:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 08/07/2005 17:41:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 20/07/2005 12:23:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THERE SHOULD NOW BE NO MORE CHANGES! 
¬*			SEE ROSS/LUCI/MIKE!
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 05/08/2005 16:25:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++