¬ Text file containing all the strings for scripted historic events

¬ Events from the original Rome
{ESPIONAGE_IN_CARTHAGE_TITLE}				The Epic Cycle
{A_NEW_RELIGION_TITLE}					Death of Palamedes
{ERUPTION_AT_ETNA_TITLE}					Winegrowers
{PLAGUE_IN_MACEDONIA_TITLE}				Wrath of Achilles
{STOIC_PHILOSOPHY_TITLE}					Deaths of Achilles and Ajax
{HAND_PUMP_INVENTED_TITLE}					Return of Philoctetes
{LIBRARIAN_AT_ALEXANDRIA_TITLE}				Sack of Troy
{GREAT_LIBRARY_COMPLETED_TITLE}				Returns
{THROUGH_A_GLASS_CLEARLY_TITLE}				Rise of Aegisthus
{ARCHIMEDES_SCREW_TITLE}					Gathering at Corinth
{GREEK_LOGIC_TITLE}						A Mother's Blood
{STAR_CATALOGUE_TITLE}					Punishment of Neoptolemus
{PLAGUE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_TITLE}				Aeneas and Dido
{RITES_OF_BACCHUS_BANNED_TITLE}				Helen in Egypt?
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_PONTUS_TITLE}				Aeneas and the Will of Zeus
{CONCRETE_INVENTED_TITLE}					Odysseus' Vengeance
{ERUPTION_AT_VESUVIUS_TITLE}				Telegony
{PHILOSOPHY_IS_FOPPISH_TITLE}				Children of Heracles
{ASTRONOMY_ADVANCES_TITLE}				Colonisation of Ionia
{LEX_AEBUTIA_TITLE}						Lyric Poetry
{ROMAN_STOICISM_TITLE}					Tragic Poetry
{LEX_PAPIRA_TITLE}						Mythography
{PLAGUE_IN_ITALY_TITLE}					The Hellenistic Revolution
{VESTAL_VIRGIN_STRUCK_DOWN_TITLE}				Latin Literature
{A_NEW_MAN_GAIUS_MARIUS_TITLE}				Byzantium and Classical Culture
{DE_RERUM_NATURA_TITLE}					De Rerum Natura
{PLAGUE_IN_ASIA_MINOR_TITLE}				Plague in Asia Minor
{LEX_POMPEIA_TITLE}						Lex Pompeia
{DE_MATERIA_MEDICA_TITLE}					De Materia Medica
{JULIAN_CALENDAR_TITLE}					Julian Calendar
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_IBERIA_TITLE}				Earthquake in Iberia
{THE_AENEID_TITLE}						The Aeneid
{LEX_ADULTERIIS_COERCENDIS_TITLE}				Lex Adulteriis Coercendis
{TROUBLE_IN_JUDEA_TITLE}					Trouble in Judea
{LEX_FUFIA_CANINIA_TITLE}					Lex Fufia Caninia
{ESPIONAGE_IN_CARTHAGE_BODY}				The story of the Trojan War, surely the greatest and most famous event of the entire collection of Greek heroic myths, was contained within a series of epic poems that are collectively known as the 'Epic' or 'Trojan' Cycle. The most famous of the epic poems are the Iliad ('Ilias' in Greek) and the Odyssey ('Odysseia'), which deal with the wrath of Achilles and Odysseus' return home to Ithaca respectively, though there were many other poems on the subject as well, many of which are no longer known. The Epic Cycle as we have it today consists of eight poems, of which only the Iliad and the Odyssey survive in full; the other poems survive in papyrus fragments, brief quotations by ancient Greek and Roman literary scholars, paraphrases by mythographers, and so on.\n\nThe Epic Cycle begins with a poem called the 'Cypria' ('Kypria'). The poem began with Zeus' decision that the Earth was over-populated, and that it needed to be 'unburdened' of a large number of men. It went on to tell of the Seven Against Thebes, the wedding of Peleus and Thetis, the build-up to the Trojan War and then various events that may be recognised from the Iliad, such as Zeus' plan to detach Achilles from the rest of the Achaean army. It is often attributed to Stasinus, and was apparently written after the Iliad, in that it appears to be specifically structured as a 'prequel'.\n\nThe Iliad itself is the most famous poem, and needs little description here. It begins with Agamemnon taking the slave girl Briseis, a prize of honour, from Achilles, who angrily refuses to help the Achaean army any more. This is followed by Hector's success on the battlefield, almost destroying the Achaean army, until Achilles' companion Patroclus is slain by the Trojan hero. This rouses Achilles from his sloth, and the poem climaxes with Achilles facing and slaying Hector. Finally, however, King Priam persuades Achilles to be merciful and return Hector's body, so that it can be given the proper funeral rites.\n\nThe next poem in the Cycle is the Aethiopis ('Aithiopis'), by Arctinus of Miletus, and covers the arrival of the Trojan allies Memnon and Penthesilea from Ethiopia and the Amazons. It describes how Achilles slew them both, and then narrates Achilles' own death, shot in the ankle by Paris. The Aethiopis is followed by the Little Iliad ('Mikra Ilias') of Lesches of Pyrrha, which relates various episodic incidents from the death of Achilles to the building of the Trojan horse. Aristotle criticised the Little Iliad for having far too long a storyline for a single epic poem (a criticism that could equally be levelled at many modern movies such as King Kong or The Dark Knight).\n\nThe final destruction of Troy is narrated in the Sack of Troy ('Iliou Persis'), apparently also by Arctinus of Miletus, and the story of the immediate aftermath is taken up by the Returns ('Nostoi') by either Agias of Troezen or Eumelus of Corinth. This poem tells of the storm that scattered the Achaean heroes as they attempted to sail home, and concludes with the final arrival of Agamemnon and Menelaus at their respective homes. The Odyssey, also by Homer, describes Odysseus' ten-year journey home after being driven off-course in the storm and then incurring the wrath of Poseidon, who prevents his return until the god is finally appeased. On returning home, Odysseus finds that a host of suitors, who believe him dead, have been trying to woo his loyal wife; finally Odysseus and his son Telemachus massacre every single one in a truly epic bloodbath. The last poem of the Cycle, the Telegony ('Telegonia'), tells of Odysseus' return home via Thesprotia, and then how Telegonus, a son of Circe by Odysseus, who comes to Ithaca and accidentally kills his father. When Telegonus and Odysseus recognise one another, they are reconciled, just as Odysseus dies. Finally Telegonus marries Penelope, and Telemachus marries Circe.\n\nEpic poetry is one of the earliest known forms of Greek poetry, and derives its name from the Greek 'epos', which literally means 'word' in English. Epic poems are usually characterised by their narrative structure, heroic subject matter and hexameter rhythm. While ancient poetry rarely employed rhyme, all ancient poetry was structured on patterns of rhythm, of which the hexameter was one of the best known and most widely used. The rhythm or metre ('metron') of each line ('stichos') of poetry was separated into six ('hex') sections known as 'feet', or 'podes' in Greek - hence the name 'hexameter'. Each foot may contain a variety of metrical configurations based around long or short syllables; ancient Greek rhythm was based on quantity (length) of syllable, rather than on syllabic emphasis, as modern English rhythm is.
{A_NEW_RELIGION_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nAt the outbreak of war between the Achaeans and the Trojans, quick-witted Odysseus realised that this would be a deadly and dangerous battle. Although bound by the Oath of Tyndareus, he attempted to get out of his obligations by pretending to be mad. As 'proof' of his madness, he even started ploughing his own fields with salt. Agamemnon sent Palamedes to summon Odysseus to join the army, and when he saw Odysseus' 'madness', Palamedes guessed what the wily hero was up to. He took Odysseus' young son Telemachus and placed him in front of the plough. Odysseus, not wanting to cut his own son in two with the ploughshare, had to drop his disguise and accompany Palamedes to the Achaean fleet. He never forgave him.\n\nDuring the war, Odysseus was sent to the Thracian area to obtain grain for the Achaean army, but came back with nothing. Palamedes mocked him for this, and so Odysseus challenged him to do better; Palamedes subsequently returned with large quantities of grain. To get revenge, Odysseus decided to forge an incriminating letter from Priam to Palamedes, which was 'found', along wth some Trojan gold, in his tent. As a result, Agamemnon condemned Palamedes for treason and had him stoned to death.\n\nLater on, when Palamedes' father Nauplius discovered what had happened, he travelled to the Achaean army in Mysia to obtain justice, but was turned away. When he returned to Achaea, he travelled to the wives of the various heroes who were away and told them that their husbands were planning to return with Trojan concubines to take their places. This began to turn many of the Achaean wives against their menfolk...
{ERUPTION_AT_ETNA_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nAfter several years of fighting, tired and hungry, the Achaean army was on the point of mutiny. They had come to the end of their supplies and lost many thousands of men. While they had taken everything they could from Mysia and the Thracian coast, the Trojans still had large amounts of food stored up in their city. Agamemnon had to act fast in order to keep control of the situation.\n\nThe 'Winegrowers' were the daughters of Anius, son of Apollo and king of Delos, and had been granted the power to produce oil, wine and grain spontaneously from the earth. Agamemnon decided to send for the Winegrowers, and so the three sisters Elais, Oeno and Spermo were brought to Mysia to supply the Achaean warriors. This was just in time, and mutiny was staved-off for the moment.
{PLAGUE_IN_MACEDONIA_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nTowards the end of the Trojan War, in the ninth year, a priest of Apollo named Chryses came to the Achaean army to request that Agamemnon return his daughter Chryseis, who had been captured in an Achaean raid. Agamemnon refused, and so Chryses prayed to Apollo to send a plague to curse the Achaean army. In the end, Agamemnon realised the need to return Chryseis in order to save his men from the disease, yet he still wanted a prize of honour. So he decided, unwisely, to take Achilles' prize slave girl Briseis. In his great wrath, Achilles decided to retire from the fighting.\n\nDespite some warriors such as Diomedes still having success in battle, the Trojan commander Hector soon realised his opportunity to attack the Achaeans while they were without the help of Achilles and the Myrmidons. After a few days, the Trojan forces began to drive the Achaean army back to its camp and ships on the seashore, and some Trojan heroes even managed to penetrate the Achaean defences. It seemed that the Achaean army would be doomed, until Achilles' companion Patroclus, unable to stand by any longer, donned Achilles' armour and went to meet Hector in battle. Hector, being the mightier warrior, slew Patroclus. This turned out to be a big mistake.\n\nWhen Achilles learned that his boon companion Patroclus had been killed by Hector, he vowed to return to the fight and kill every single Trojan. He quickly routed the Trojan army single-handedly, and advanced so far that the local river-god Scamander rose up to stop him. Though Scamander soon sent Achilles running away in fear, but fortunately Hera, Athena and Hephaestus intervened to save him. A battle of the gods followed, and Achilles came very close to open fighting with the archer-god Apollo, which would have been deadly for the mortal had he not withdrawn. At last Achilles managed to draw Hector out from behind the walls of Troy to face him in a duel, and with the rather unfair help of Athena, slew him in open combat.\n\nAfter abusing the dead body of Hector for several days, Achilles was approached by Priam himself, who had managed to sneak into the Achaean camp. Priam managed to appeal to his enemy's pity, and Achilles finally came to realise that, ultimately, all men must die and are equally subject to the whims of the gods. When his anger subsided, Achilles finally agreed to return Hector's body to the Trojans for funerary rites, and even committed the entire Achaean army to a truce for the duration of the Trojan funeral games.
{STOIC_PHILOSOPHY_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nNot long after the funeral of the Trojan hero Hector, the Amazon queen Penthesilea came to join the battle against the Achaeans. Some say that she slew Achilles, and that at the request of Achilles' mother Thetis he was resurrected. This is probably not true. At any rate, Achilles eventually faced Penthesilea in battle and killed her, though he was struck by her great beauty even in death. The rough Achaean commoner Thersites taunted Achilles for this and poked out the dead queen's eyes, for which Achilles slew him on the spot.\n\nSoon afterwards, the Ethiopian Memnon arrived at Troy and also faced Achilles in battle. First Memnon tried to kill Nestor, but Nestor's son Antilochus jumped in the way and took the fatal blow himself. Then Achilles squared up to Memnon and cut him down. Achilles routed the Trojans again, chasing them to their city, but this time the gods decided that he had killed too many people; the Trojan prince Paris, aided by Apollo, shot a poisoned arrow from the walls, hitting Achilles' ankle. This was the end of Achilles, the greatest of the Achaeans.\n\nAfter Achilles' death, there was a competition as to who should win Achilles' arms, and it came down to either Odysseus or Ajax. Odysseus had fought off the Trojans while Ajax had carried Achilles' body off the field. For one reason or another, Achilles' arms were awarded to Odysseus, and Ajax, mad with grief, decided to kill all the Achaean leaders and then himself. Ajax was the second-greatest of the Achaeans after Achilles, and would have succeeded, but the goddess Athena deluded him into slaying a herd of cattle by mistake. When Ajax came to his senses once more, he realised that he could not live with such great dishonour, and so went out into the wilderness and fell on his sword.
{HAND_PUMP_INVENTED_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nPhiloctetes, the son of King Poeas of Meliboea in Thessaly, had been another one of the Achaean leaders who had competed for the hand of the beautiful Helen and had sworn the Oath of Tyndareus. When the Achaean army set sail for Troy, Philoctetes accompanied it. However, when he stopped at the small island of Chryse in the Aegean, he unwittingly trespassed into the shrine of the nymph Chryse (after whom the island was named). By way of a rather unfair punishment, Philoctetes received a nasty wound to his foot, and the Achaeans, following Odysseus' advice decided to abandon him on the island of Lemnos.\n\nMany years later, with Achilles and Hector both dead, and seemingly no way for the Achaean forces to break the deadlock and get past the Trojan walls, Odysseus managed to kidnap the Trojan prophet Helenus. The Achaeans forced him to reveal how Troy would fall, and he told them that the city would only be captured when the Achaeans had possession of the bow and arrows of Heracles. Realising that Philoctetes was the last person to have these (Heracles had gifted them to Poeas), Odysseus and Diomedes rushed back to Lemnos to bring Philoctetes back. Odysseus - who did not get on well with Philoctetes - worked out a way to trick him into handing the items over, but Diomedes refused to take such a dishonest course of action. In the end Heracles, now a god, came from Olympus and told Philoctetes that his foot would be healed if he went back to the Achaean army, which he did.\n\nOn arrival outside Troy, Philoctetes' foot was healed by Podalirius, the son of Thessalian Asclepius (now a healing god). He joined the fighting and almost killed Paris in combat, but divisions among the Achaean leadership meant that Paris got away. Most of the Achaeans had by now given up hope of capturing Troy by storm, and only Philoctetes and Neoptolemus - who were new arrivals and had not experienced the years of hardship - remained in favour of assaulting the walls. With the capture of Troy apparently not any more likely, despite the presence of Heracles' bow and arrows, the Achaeans would have to find a new plan.
{LIBRARIAN_AT_ALEXANDRIA_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nWith no obvious way to capture Troy by a frontal attack - they had been trying for ten years - the Achaeans realised that it was time for a new plan. Fortunately for them, they had exactly the man for the job, cunning Odysseus of Ithaca. Odysseus suggested that the Achaeans try a trojan horse (quite literally). They would build a large, hollow horse statue out of wood, and hide several heroes within; the Trojans would, hopefully, bring the statue into the city.\n\nThe craftsman Epeius built a large wooden horse statue (with the help of Athena), on which he inscribed the following:\n\n"The Achaeans dedicate this thank-offering to Athena for their return home."\n\nThe horse was then packed with forty heroes, including Odysseus, Philoctetes, Agamemnon, Diomedes, Menelaus, Idomeneus, Thersander and others. The Achaean army burned its camp and withdrew out of sight to the island of Tenedos nearby. When the Trojans discovered the horse in the morning, they decided to bring it within the city. The Trojan priest Laocoon tried to stop them from doing this, uttering the famous line recorded in Latin by Virgil:\n\n"Timeo Danaos et dona ferentes" - "I fear Greeks, even when bearing gifts."\n\nHowever, Poseidon sent two sea snakes to strangle Laocoon and his two sons before anyone listened to his advice. That night, the Trojans began to feast and celebrate their apparent victory. Finally, when most of the Trojans were either drunk or asleep, the Achaean heroes began to emerge from the horse. They made their way to one of the gatehouses and gave a signal to the Achaean army, which was just marching back up from the shore. The gates were opened, and the Achaeans began to swarm in. The Trojans were in no state to resist, and within a short time the slaughter and pillage began. It would last well into the next day.\n\nSome Trojans did try to fight back. Aeneas gathered some companions, stole some Achaean armour and standards to disguise themselves, and began to launch surprise attacks on roaming Achaean warriors in the streets. Nonetheless, it was futile to resist. Neoptolemus broke into the royal palace and slew Priam while he was clinging to an altar to Zeus. Menelaus slew Deiphobus (who had taken up residence with Helen after Paris' death) and nearly killed Helen too. Fortunately for her, he was so overcome by her beauty that he threw his sword down. Ajax the Lesser (not the son of Telamon) caught the prophetess Cassandra and raped her on the altar of Athena. Hector's infant son Astyanax was thrown off the walls of the city.\n\nWith Troy fallen, the city was set alight, and the Achaeans began to divide the spoils. Agamemnon received Cassandra, Neoptolemus took Hector's wife Andromache, and Odysseus was given Hecuba, Priam's wife.\n\nAs the Sun rose over the devastated city, Aeneas gathered a small group of survivors on the slopes of Mt Ida just outside the city. Gradually more and more survivors made their way out of the chaos to join them, until eventually Prince Aeneas found that he had a small army at his command. They could not return to Troy, and so they set out, seeking their future in a foreign land...
{GREAT_LIBRARY_COMPLETED_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nDuring their sack of the city of Troy the Achaeans committed many great impieties. The gods were most displeased at the Achaeans' destruction and pillaging of their temples, and so decided that most should not return home safely. Nestor was the only hero who was allowed to return home straight away, owing to his noble conduct throughout the Trojan War.\n\nAs the Achaean ships set sail, a tremendous storm scattered them far and wide. Zeus struck the ship of Ajax the Lesser with a thunderbolt; his sailors managed to find refuge on a rock, but Poseidon shattered it, and Ajax sank to his doom. Diomedes was cast adrift to Lycia, where King Lycus was on the point of sacrificing him to Ares (fortunately his daughter Callirhoe rescued him). Next Diomedes accidentally pitched up in Attica, where the Athenians (mistaking him for an enemy), attacked him and his men. Neoptolemus was sent first to the land of the Thracian Ciconians, and finally ended up in Epirus. Menelaus washed up in Egypt. The one who had the most famous and lively journey, however, was Odysseus, who would wander for ten whole years, encountering many peoples and monsters.
{THROUGH_A_GLASS_CLEARLY_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nIn days gone by Atreus, the father of Agamemnon and Menelaus seized the throne of Mycenae from his brother Thyestes. Thyestes had an affair with Atreus' wife Aerope, and in revenge Atreus secretly killed Thyestes' sons and served them up to him at dinner. On learning of this impious act, Thyestes asked an oracle how he could best get revenge. The oracle told him to father a son with his own daughter, Pelopia, and that this son would punish the family of Atreus. The young boy, Aegisthus, was abandoned and brought up by Atreus, but when Atreus sent him to kill Thyestes, he recognised him for his true father and returned and slew Atreus instead. Thereafter Aegisthus and Thyestes ruled Mycenae jointly, until Agamemnon and Menelaus, with the help of King Tyndareus of Sparta, returned and overthrew them.\n\nAegisthus was not finished, however. Many years later, when Agamemnon finally returned from the Trojan War, Aegisthus was waiting to take power in Mycenae again. Agamemnon's wife Clytaemnestra would never forgive her husband for sacrificing their daughter Iphigenia (in order to obtain the gods' approval for the departure of the Achaean fleet), and began an affair with Aegisthus after Agamemnon left for Troy. When Agamemnon finally returned to Mycenae in triumph, leading with him the captive Trojan prophetess Cassandra, Aegisthus and Clytaemnestra were ready to strike. Cassandra could see her terrible fate, but there was no way for her to save herself. When Agamemnon was taking a bath Aegisthus and Clytaemnestra broke in and stabbed him to death; Cassandra was finished off as she lay on a bed. The family of Thyestes was back in power.
{ARCHIMEDES_SCREW_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nAfter the Trojan War the Greek army was scattered by a terrible storm. When most of the survivors had managed to make their way home at last, they found themselves driven from their thrones. For Nauplius, having failed to obtain satisfaction from the Achaean leaders for the unjust execution of his son Palamedes, returned to Achaea and persuaded several of the leaders' wives to take up with lovers. He went first to Crete, where he persuaded Idomeneus' wife Meda to begin an affair with Leucus. He seized power, and prevented Idomeneus from landing in Crete on his return. Later Leucus murdered Meda and her daughter by Idomeneus, Clisithyra.\n\nUnable to go home, Idomeneus sailed to Corinth in the Peloponnese. He was soon joined by Diomedes, who had been driven away from Argos, and by Teucer, who had been exiled from Salamis by his father Telamon for failing to prevent the death of his brother Ajax. Together the Achaean heroes planned to mass their remaining followers and launch a series of wars to restore each other to their respective thrones. However, wise Nestor advised against this, persuading them that Achaea should not be set on fire with yet more war and bloodshed, having only just won the Trojan War. They took his advice, and went their separate ways. Diomedes and Idomeneus both set sail for Italy, where they would make their new homes.
{GREEK_LOGIC_BODY}						The poets relate...\n\nAfter the murder of Agamemnon, Aegisthus and his new wife Clytaemnestra took power in Mycenae. Their first task was to consolidate their rule, and that meant killing Agamemnon's surviving relatives, especially his young son Orestes. However, Orestes was smuggled out of Mycenae by his sister and his nurse Arsinoe and taken to the court of King Strophius in Phocis. There he made friends with Strophius' son Pylades, who would become a life-long friend of his.\n\nWhen they had grown old and bold enough, Orestes and Pylades planned to return to Mycenae to take revenge on Aegisthus and Clytaemnestra. They travelled to the outskirts of the city, where they encountered a small peasant's hut. There, by a strange coincidence, they found Orestes' sister Electra, who had been married to a poor Mycenaean peasant (Clytaemnestra could not bring herself to murder her daughter). The three plotted together how to kill the usurpers, and finally they hit upon a plan. First Orestes ambushed Aegisthus as he was sacrificing to the nymphs and cut him down; the royal guard, rather than attempting to protect Aegisthus, applauded the deed. Next Electra lured Clytaemnestra to her country hut, and Orestes sprang on her as she entered, driving a sword through her chest.\n\nWracked with guilt and pursued by the avenging Furies for his matricide, Orestes fled from Mycenae and became tortured by madness...
{STAR_CATALOGUE_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nOn finally making landfall in Achaea after returning from the Trojan War, Achilles' son Neoptolemus and the elderly Phoenix travelled through the northern wilderness of Thessaly and Paeonia with their Trojan captives Helenus and Andromache (the former wife of Hector). They set out for the land of the Molossians in the West, although Phoenix died on the way and had to be buried by Neoptolemus. The young hero eventually arrived, routed the forces of the Molossian king, and took power over the land of Epirus and the islands off the coast.\n\nHowever, all would not remain well for Neoptolemus. He was married to Menelaus' daughter Hermione, but since Hermione had also been promised to Agamemnon's son Orestes, the latter managed to track Neoptolemus down at the Oracle in Pytho and slew him at the altar of Apollo. Since Neoptolemus had himself slain King Priam at an altar of Zeus, the process of an ironic death (dying in the same way that you have killed someone else) has come to be known as the 'Punishment of Neoptolemus'.
{PLAGUE_IN_ALEXANDRIA_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nDuring the sack of Troy, the Trojan prince Aeneas was able to escape the city with a large band of survivors, who gathered under his leadership on Mt Ida. The Achaeans were so busy looting the city that they either did not notice this or did not care to come out and finish them off. The Trojans built a fleet of ships and travelled to Thrace, but there they were warned by an apparition of the ghost of Priam's son Polydorus that they should move on. Next they came to King Anius of Delos, and at the temple of Apollo on the island Aeneas received instructions that seemed to indicate that the Trojans should go to Crete. However, when they arrived they were greeted by famine and sickness, and so they moved on again. Next they made landfall on the island of Zacynthus off the western coast of Achaea, and then Buthrotum in Epirus. Epirus had been conquered by Neoptolemus, the son of Achilles, but Neoptolemus had left his Trojan captive Helenus in the area to govern it for him. Helenus, who was a prophet, told Aeneas how to get to Drepanum in Sicily.\n\nWhen the Trojans arrived in Sicily, having travelled for a great length of time, Aeneas' father Ancises died. The Trojans set sail again and were caught in a terrible storm sent by Aeolus on the orders of the goddess Hera, who was still filled with rage and a desire for revenge against the Trojans on account of Paris' judgment that Aphrodite was the more beautiful goddess. When the shipwrecked Trojans washed up on land, they found themselves in North Africa, in the domains of Queen Dido of Carthage. Aeneas' mother Aphrodite, who was looking out for her son, made Dido fall in love with him and receive him hospitably. Aeneas became her consort, and started to supervise the government of the city and various public works. However, Zeus had other plans for him, and sent the god Hermes to tell Aeneas that, however soft his life in Carthage was, the father of the gods had other plans for him...
{RITES_OF_BACCHUS_BANNED_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nSome have made the curious claim that, when the Achaeans finally captured Troy, they found that Helen had never been there at all. According to poets like Euripides, Paris anchored his ship in the mouth of the Nile on the way back to Egypt. When Proteus, the king of Egypt, discovered this, he ordered Paris and Helen to be brought to Memphis. Proteus greatly respected Zeus' law of hospitality, and when he realised that Paris had violated this by stealing Helen away, he decided to punish him. However, since Paris was his own guest, he did not kill him, but rather sent him on his way back to Troy without Helen, who stayed in Egypt with Proteus. Instead the gods fashioned a phantom of Helen out of clouds, and the Trojan War was fought anyway.\n\nAt the end of the Trojan War, when the Achaean leaders had been scattered in a storm at sea on their way back to Achaea, Menelaus of Sparta, Helen's husband, eventually found himself washed up at the mouth of the Nile. When he came to Proteus' court at Memphis, he found the real Helen waiting there, and together they returned home to Sparta.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_PONTUS_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nAs Aeneas was in Carthage with Queen Dido, he was visited by the god Hermes. Aeneas had been living a comfortable, even effeminate, life with the beautiful Phoenician Queen, and Zeus was not pleased. The king of the gods had other plans for Aeneas. And so Hermes came to Aeneas to tell him that he was destined for a hard life, but a life of greatness. Aeneas made up his mind to sail to Italy to confront his destiny, though reluctantly - he was pained at having to leave Dido behind. Dido herself never recovered from the pain of losing Aeneas; she climbed atop a funeral pyre and transfixed herself with a sword. *\n\nMoving on from Libya, Aeneas sailed to Sicily, where the Trojan women, bewitched by the spiteful machinations of Hera, tried to burn the Trojan fleet to stop them moving any further. Fortunately Zeus would not allow this to happen, and the Trojan fleet set sail again for Cumae where Aeneas was to meet the famous Italian prophetess, the Sibyl. The Sibyl took him down to Hades, where he saw the departed souls of the Achaeans and Trojans, still fighting one another in death, and finally came to the Elysian Fields where he met his deceased father Anchises. Anchises revealed the future to Aeneas, telling him of the great people that he would establish in Italy among the Latins, and showing him some of the great heroes that would arise among that people, heroes like Octavianus Augustus Caesar.\n\nFrom Cumae Aeneas proceeded North along the Italian coast to the land of Latium, ruled by King Latinus, where he was promised in marriage to Latinus' daughter Lavinia. The local prince Turnus, however, was not happy; stirred to anger by the Fury Alecto (who had been sent by Hera), Turnus incited the Italian peoples to war against Aeneas and the Trojans, and once again Aeneas found himself leading his people in battle. Nonetheless, nothing can stand in the way of Zeus' will, and Aeneas' descendants would establish the greatest city in the world, greater even than Troy. The name of that city would be ROME.\n\n-------------------------------------\n\n\n\n* Some wags may notice the latent sexual imagery implicit in this!
{CONCRETE_INVENTED_BODY}					The poets relate...\n\nWhen the Achaean fleet was scattered by Poseidon on its way home from Troy, Odysseus and his men had by far the longest return home. First they came to the land of the Ciconians, and then embarked on a lengthy string of adventures. They encountered the Lotus-Eaters, who ate the fruit of the lotus, inducing permanent memory loss. Next they came to the island of the Cyclopes and dreadful man-eating Polyphemus. Odysseus managed to blind Polyphemus, and taunted him as he got away, and so Polyphemus called upon his father Poseidon to punish Odysseus. Having escaped from the Cyclopes, Odysseus came to the islands of Aeolus, the god of the winds, who granted him fair winds trapped in a bag to help him get home. With Ithaca in sight, Odysseus fell asleep; his greedy crew, thinking that the bag contained Trojan gold, opened it and let all the fair winds go.\n\nThe fleet was driven back to Aeolus, who, after an embarrassing interview with Odysseus, refused to give them any more fair winds. Next they encountered the Laestrygonians, who destroyed the greater part of the fleet, and then Circe, who tried to turn the surviving men into pigs. Odysseus and his men were carried to the ends of the Earth, where they entered Hades and encountered many deceased heroes such as Agamemnon, Achilles and Ajax; the dead Theban prophet Tiresias gave Odysseus warnings not to eat the cattle of the Sun-god Helius in Thrinacia. Odysseus set sail again, passed Circe's island of Aeaea, sailed between the monstrous Scylla and Charybdis, and encountered Thrinacie and the cattle of Helius. Odysseus' foolish men promptly ate the cattle while he was away. In punishment, Zeus destroyed the ship and killed all of Odysseus' men, leaving Odysseus himself adrift and clinging to the ship's mast. Having narrowly escaped being sucked into the whirlpool Charybdis, Odysseus drifted to the island of the nymph Calypso, who fell in love with him and kept him prisoner for seven years, promising him immortality if he would marry her. Curiously enough, Odysseus (still faithful to Penelope and eager to return home to Ithaca) did not accept this rather attractive proposition, and eventually Hermes came to order Calypso to let him go. Next Odysseus was washed up on the island of Phaeacia, where friendly King Alcinous decided to help him and put him on a convoy of ships bound for Ithaca. Finally Odysseus came home.\n\nUpon arrival, however, the situation that greeted Odysseus was not a pleasant one. He had been away from home for twenty years, and found that his palace was occupied by a throng of suitors who had been trying to persuade his wife Penelope to marry one of them. Having made contact with his faithful swineherd Eumaeus, Odysseus disguised himself as a beggar and entered the palace. Penelope, finally about to buckle to the suitors' pressure, decided to issue the ultimate challenge: she took the bow of Apollo, which Odysseus had once received from Iphitus, and said that she would marry whichever man could string it. As the suitors tried and failed, the disguised Odysseus offered to string it. Having been roundly mocked, it was eventually agreed that he should be allowed to do so. He quickly strung the bow (which, being recurved, had to be bent under the knee in a particular fashion) and then, joined by his son Telemachus and by Eumaeus, Odysseus proceeded to massacre every last one of the suitors who had been squandering his wealth.
{ERUPTION_AT_VESUVIUS_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nWhen Odysseus had been with Circe on the island of Aeaea, the two had briefly had intimate relations, and, nine months after Odysseus left the island, a son resulted. The sorceress Circe named him Telegonus, and when he came of age she revealed to him that his father was Odysseus of Ithaca. Circe sent the young man out to find his father, though unfortunately his lack of knowledge of Achaean geography led him to mistake Ithaca for Corcyra. Telegonus had decided to attack and sack Corcyra, but by accident he launched his attack on Ithaca.\n\nOdysseus and his other son Telemachus came out to face Telegonus in combat, obviously not recognising who he was. Telegonus, equally ignorant of Odysseus' identity, engaged him in a duel and slew him with the spine of a stingray. As Odysseus lay dying, he and Telegonus finally recognised one another, and Telegonus bitterly lamented what he had done. He took Odysseus' body back with him to Aeaea, along with Penelope and Telemachus, whom Circe made immortal. Circe married Telemachus, and Telegonus married Penelope.\n\nOther poets, however, say that none of this happened, and that Odysseus died peacefully of old age as Tiresias had predicted.
{PHILOSOPHY_IS_FOPPISH_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nDuring the eventful life of Heracles, the great Achaean hero fathered many, many children throughout the world. After Heracles' death, his sons were pursued by Eurystheus (who had given Heracles his labours), the king of Argos who was determined to put an end to Heracles' line. The Heraclids, as Heracles' sons are known, took refuge in Athens, and when Eurystheus came to demand their surrender, they met him in battle. Heracles' oldest son Hyllus slew Eurystheus and sent his head to Heracles' mother Alcmena.\n\nThrough Heracles, the Heraclids claimed descent from Perseus, the original founder of Mycenae. Pelops and his descendants through Atreus and Agamemnon had seized power in Mycenae from the descendants of Perseus, and so the Heraclids now wanted to claim the land back as their own. They returned from Athens to the Peloponnese and ravaged the land, but had to retreat after a plague arose. An oracle declared that they had returned before the proper time. They retreated, and after a second and third attempt they finally did battle with Tisamenus, the last of the Pelopid line, and slew him, reinstating Perseid (now Heraclid) rule over the land.\n\nIn the Classical period, the Spartans and other Peloponnesian Dorians would claim descent from the Heraclids.
{ASTRONOMY_ADVANCES_BODY}				The poets relate...\n\nThe Ionians are the descendants of Ion, son of Xuthus, the son of Hellen, the son of Deucalion, who survived the Flood. They originally made their home in the land of Aegialus in the North of the Peloponnese, but after the Heraclids slew Tisamenus and captured the cities of Mycenae and Argos, the 'Achaeans' of those areas fled North-West to Aegialus and drove out the Ionians. The Ionians themselves fled first to Athens. The Athenian king Melanthus allowed them to settle there. Melanthus' son Codrus succeeded him as King of Athens, but was killed in battle when the Heraclids attempted to capture the city.\n\nCodrus' sons quarrelled over who would succeed him; Neileus refused to accept his older brother Medon as king, because he had a lame foot. However, the Oracle at Delphi announced that Medon was indeed the rightful king, and so Neileus decided to set out and colonise a foreign land. He invited anyone who wished to follow him, and they set sail for the East, landing in Phrygia. Most of the people who came with him were Ionians, though they were joined by many others from throughout the land of the Hellenes. They colonised a large area of the Phrygian coastline and the islands of the Aegean Sea.\n\nIn the Classical period, the Athenians would use this alleged Ionian connection to justify their imposition of Athenian power over a large swathe of the Aegean Sea and Asia Minor coastline.
{LEX_AEBUTIA_BODY}						While the Epic Cycle is the source for the majority of our knowledge of ancient Greek mythology, there are many other sources as well that must be used to supplement the epic poems. One of the earliest genres of Greek poetry besides epic was 'lyric' poetry (also known in Greek as 'melikos', from 'melos', meaning 'song'), so-called because it was performed to the music of a lyre. It seems to have emerged in the Archaic Greek period, especially from the seventh century B.C. These poems were relatively short, much shorter than epic, and would be composed either for special occasions or for more casual enjoyment at symposia.\n\nThe scholars of Hellenistic Alexandria (third to second centuries B.C.) made a list of nine lyric poets to be considered canonical. These were:\n\nAlcman (7th cent. B.C.)\nSappho (c. 600 B.C.)\nAlcaeus (c. 600 B.C.)\nAnacreon (6th cent. B.C.)\nStesichorus (6th cent. B.C.)\nIbycus (6th cent. B.C.)\nSimonides (6th cent. B.C.)\nPindar (5th cent. B.C.)\nBacchylides (5th cent. B.C.)\n\nThere were also various other lyric poets, such as Tyrtaeus, though these are the most famous. Often they would take a specific theme and then expound on this theme using one or more short stories from mythology. For instance, Pindar, who wrote epinician poetry (poetry in commemoration of competitors' victories in athletic competitions such as the Olympic Games), would weave many neat mythological stories and comparisons into his work in order to glorify the patron who commissioned the poem. An excellent example would be his poem Pythian 1, composed to celebrate the victory of Hiero of Syracuse in the chariot racing at the Pythian Games of 470. Hiero, a Syracusan tyrant of Dorian descent, had recently defeated the Etruscans and Carthaginians when they attempted to conquer the Greeks of Italy and Sicily, and had just founded the city of Aetna (at the foot of the volcano Mt Etna). Pindar takes the story of Zeus' subjugation of the hundred-headed monster Typhon (also known as Typhoeus) and his imposition of law and order, and uses it as a comparison with Hiero's subjugation of the barbarian 'monsters' of Etruria and Carthage.
{ROMAN_STOICISM_BODY}					Tragic poetry, composed for performance at theatrical festivals, is a particularly rich source for the myths of the ancient Greeks. This poetry lies at the root of modern European theatre, and seems to have been derived from a 6th-century religious ritual involving choral singing and dancing around a goat sacrifice - the Greek word 'tragoidia' literally means 'goat-singing'. According to Aristotle, who wrote at length about the theory of poetry in his 'Poetics', this form of drama developed from the improvisations of the leader of choral dithyrambs, hymns sung in honour of the god Dionysus (who was the patron of the theatre as well as of wine), though it is not certain if he is right about this. At any rate, in the late sixth century B.C. one of the singers would engage in solos or monologues; a second was added, allowing for dialogue, and in the course of the fifth century a third person would be added, thus allowing for dramatic interchange between a wide variety of characters in the same play (while two characters talked on stage, the third could be changing his mask off-stage).\n\nGreek tragic actors would wear masks called 'prosopa', which may be translated with the Latin 'persona' or the English 'person' (hence why modern cast lists are sometimes entitled 'Dramatis Personae'). These masks bore fixed expressions that defined the characters that the actors played. Tragedy, being a very high register of poetic performance, took its subjects almost entirely from mythical pre-history (with some exceptions such as Aeschylus' play 'The Persians', which was about Xerxes' invasion in 479 B.C.). Although most of them had unhappy endings, contrary to popular belief it was possible to have a tragedy with a 'happy' ending as well, such as Euripides' 'Ion'.\n\nBy way of a quirk of history, the tragedy of ancient Athens became the most widely known and admired in the ancient world, and in the Roman Empire the three canonical poets Aeschylus, Sophocles and Euripides came to be heavily studied in schools, with the result that, while manuscripts of their plays were frequently copied (and so survived to the modern period), many manuscripts of other playwrights were gradually lost and survive only in fragments, if at all.\n\nOf the three tragic playwrights, it is the opinion of the historical consultant of the 'Aristeia' mod that Euripides was undoubtedly the best, and his final play 'The Bacchae' was the peak of tragic poetry, an absolutely sublime work of literature that you players should all go and read.
{LEX_PAPIRA_BODY}						As prose scholarship became more popular in the fifth century B.C. and afterwards, some writers tried their hand and creating collections of myths, usually arranged in chronological order. These men are known as 'mythographers', though it should also be noted that other writers such as historians often made reference to myths in their works as well (Herodotus complains, however, that poetry and myth does not serve to provide an accurate guide to history, an ironic statement considering the fact that he obviously made up large sections of his own material off the top of his head).\n\nThe genre of mythography was apparently begun by the Greek writer Euhemerus of Macedonia in the fourth century, though there were many others too. The Hellenistic period, with its enthusiasm for academic scholarship, produced great mythographers such as Apollodorus, whose 'Bibliotheca' ('Library') provided much of the information for this mod.
{PLAGUE_IN_ITALY_BODY}					After Alexander the Great's death, the whole area from Greece and Egypt to Afghanistan and India was ruled by Graeco-Macedonian successor kingdoms. After an initial period of infighting and extremely confusing wars in the last twenty years of the fourth century, the third century saw the 'Hellenistic' kingdoms settle down into more permanent states ruled by fairly stable dynasties, most notably the Ptolemies in Egypt and the Seleucids in the Middle East.\n\nIn Alexandria the Ptolemies established a famous Library and 'Museum' (a temple to the Muses) and extended patronage to scholars and poets from throughout the Greek world. This exciting new environment for Greek literature gave birth to an explosion of astonishing innovation in both poetry and scholarship. The new literature produced in Alexandria by these 'Hellenistic' writers was quite firmly rooted in Greek traditions (and so Greek myth still provided much of the inspiration), but they began to experiment much more. \n\nCallimachus of Cyrene, one of the greatest poets in history (you can forget all the modern nonsense), produced a large corpus of extremely witty and intelligent epigrams (short poems of roughly four to twenty lines' length). He was apparently accused of being unable to write a 'mega poiema' ('great poem') like the ancients, and so set out to prove his critics wrong. He produced two known epics, the Hecale and the Aetia, but these were epic poems with a difference. For a start, although they technically conformed to the requirements of an epic poem (hexameter rhythm, heroic subject matter etc.) they were much shorter than you might expect, and contained Callimachus' trademark wit and intellect. The Hecale tells the story of how Theseus of Athens slew the Marathonian bull, though from the surviving fragments it is clear that most of the poem deals with Theseus' conversations with Hecale, a simple peasant woman of noble lineage who gives him hospitality at Marathon (and provides the name of the poem!). Even more uniquely, the Aetia is a collection of anecdotes about heroic mythology that are not bound together by a storyline or narrative structure, but rather by themes such as love, journeys home, justice and so forth.\n\nThere were many other great poets besides. Apollonius of Rhodes composed an Argonautica, a short epic about Jason and the Argonauts that is best known for its third book, in which the Colchian princess (and witch) Medea falls in love with the handsome Greek hero Jason as he tries to obtain the golden fleece. The focus on her love, and the truly groundbreaking psychological insights that Apollonius brings to the idea of love within poetry, make this one of the great Hellenistic works. Mention should also be made of Theocritus, whose 'Idylls' (which deal with subjects ranging from the monstrous Cyclops Polyphemus' unrequited love for the nymph Galatea to the gossiping of two course Greek women in Alexandria) are real gems and genuinely delightful to read.
{VESTAL_VIRGIN_STRUCK_DOWN_BODY}				From the second century B.C. onwards, the power of the Hellenistic kingdoms began to wane, and from then on Rome would be the greatest power in the European world until the rise of the Frankish Empire in the 8th century A.D. In terms of cultural heritage, the Romans had some literary traditions on which to draw (such as the epic poet Ennius or the rather lacklustre and distinctly unfunny comic playwright Plautus), but even the most bigoted Roman xenophobe had to admit that the growing Empire would have to base its culture on that of Greece. In the first centuries B.C. and A.D., with the Roman Republic making the transition to the Roman Principate and the one-man rule of Augustus, Latin literature began to flourish in its own right, but not without heavy inspiration from Greek culture.\n\nThe most famous Latin poets who deal with Greek mythology are Virgil and Ovid, both of whom were strongly influenced by Greek Hellenistic literature and did much to reshape and rework it in their own pieces. Ovid's epic poems, the 'Metamorphoses' ('Transformations') and the 'Heroides' ('Wives of Heroes') have their roots in the archaic Greek catalogues such as Hesiod's epic poem the 'Eoae', but they derive their wit and lightness of touch from the Hellenistic poets. The Metamorphoses (a very useful source of information for this mod) are strongly reminiscent of Callimachus' Aetia, in that they do not have a storyline, but are rather based on the theme of people and animals changing shape.\n\nIt is necessary, however, to focus considerable attention on Virgil, whose great epic poem the 'Aeneid' was deliberately composed to rival both the Iliad and the Odyssey and indeed to surpass them. In the judgment of this mod's historical consultant, the Aeneid is indeed an even finer epic poem than the Homeric works, and that is really saying something. In telling the story first of Aeneas' journey from Troy and then of his war in Latium, Virgil takes both of the main elements of the Iliad and Odyssey and reverses them. Even the first line of the poem is notable:\n\n"Arma virumque cano..." - "I sing of arms and a man"\n\nIn three words, Virgil has announced that he is going to do both the Iliad (arms) and the Odyssey (a man) in one go, and do them even better, which he does. Aeneas' love for Dido and his journey to Hades are particularly well known and loved, though the last six books (often overlooked) are extremely fine in their own right as well. What is fascinating about the Aeneid is that it builds on the incredible and innovative psychological insights of Hellenistic poets such as Apollonius and uses them to craft a character for Aeneas that develops gradually throughout the poem in a way that cannot fail to fascinate the reader.\n\nThere were various other Latin poets who followed on from Virgil and the other 'Silver-Age' poets, some of whom deserve praise (such as Lucan) and some of whom may be passed over without too much anxiety (such as Statius). Though you should keep an eye out for some others, especially Petronius, whose bawdy and often extremely tasteless 'Satyricon' is a hilarious and extremely enjoyable read, and reworks a lot of Greek mythology in really quite innovative ways. Even the (understandably) often overlooked paedophile scene at the beginning is surprisingly fun.
{A_NEW_MAN_GAIUS_MARIUS_BODY}				You should spare a thought for the fact that a gulf of nearly two thousand years separates the modern day from the last of the really famous Classical mythological poetry. How did we come to have it all in our possession?\n\nAfter the fall of the Western Roman Empire in 476, the Latin world of Western Europe would drop into something of a cultural and intellectual Dark Age (though not as bad as is often assumed) until it was revived through Greek and Arabic stimulation. Often overlooked, however, the Eastern Roman Empire - which has been named 'Byzantine' by modern historians - survived the fall of its rather weak Western counterpart by a thousand years, only succumbing to the Ottoman Turks in A.D. 1453. Though the Byzantine Empire went through its own ups and downs, its scholars preserved a great wealth of Classical literature and learning in a period when Western Europeans had forgotten that such a thing even existed.\n\nIt may be surprising, but much of the information for this mod has actually been derived not directly from the ancient Greeks or Romans, but from Byzantine scholars such as Photius, the ninth-century Christian Patriarch of Constantinople. He had access to a large number of Classical texts (which were later lost in a series of wars and disasters) that do not survive today, and in his 'Bibliotheca' ('Library') he preserves summaries of the contents of many of these. Likewise, in the tenth-century encyclopaedia (a Byzantine invention, incidentally) known as the 'Suda' we have an invaluable wealth of detail and information about the Classical world and Classical mythology.\n\nHaving said all that, you should NOT think that the only important and interesting achievement of the Byzantines was to preserve ancient culture in a sort of time capsule. The Byzantines had many fascinating cultural achievements of their own, and have suffered in the modern period from the bigoted and arrogant assumptions of Western scholars who have been too blind to pay much, if any, attention to this great civilisation. Fortunately, in recent years more and more people have begun to pay attention to the Byzantines, and this problem is being gradually solved.
{DE_RERUM_NATURA_BODY}					Until now Titus Lucretius Carus has been best known as a poet and philosopher, but in the book De Rerum Natura or 'On the Nature of the Universe' he shows himself to be a master of Epicurean thought. He also claims that matter is composed of miniscule particles called 'atoms'.
{PLAGUE_IN_ASIA_MINOR_BODY}				Plague has swept through the towns and cities of Asia Minor, leaving many dead. Already the prudent citizens of Greek, Italian and Egyptian cities have closed their gates and ports to anyone from the region.
{LEX_POMPEIA_BODY}						This new law grants rights to certain foreigners, allowing them to marry and trade with Roman citizens. It even allows them the chance to obtain Roman citizenship!
{DE_MATERIA_MEDICA_BODY}					Pedanius Dioscorides of Cilicia has published his great work cataloguing all the plants he knows with healing properties. He has also listed all the poisonous ones, along with antidotes, making the book the major medical work to date.
{JULIAN_CALENDAR_BODY}					After much careful thought a new calendar has been approved for use in Roman lands. The old calendar had become hopelessly out of step with the seasons. This new calendar resets the year to what it should be, and then cleverly keeps harmony in the lunar and solar years by adding an extra day to the calendar every four years.
{EARTHQUAKE_IN_IBERIA_BODY}				The Iberian city of Saguntum has been struck by a great earthquake, undoubtedly visited upon the people by Neptune. Many have been killed and the temple has collapsed.
{THE_AENEID_BODY}						Virgil has completed his epic retelling of Roman history in the style of Homer. It is a work of genius, and much appreciated by the Romans for its poetic accuracy.
{LEX_ADULTERIIS_COERCENDIS_BODY}				The Roman Senate have passed a new law making marital unfaithfulness a public crime. To commit adultery now carries the sentence of death or, in some cases, banishment from Rome for the lovers.
{TROUBLE_IN_JUDEA_BODY}					The client ruler of Judea appears to have gone slightly mad. He has ordered the slaughter of all new-born infants within his lands. His disturbing order was promulagated after a visit by three Zoroastrian philosophers that caused him many sleepless nights.
{LEX_FUFIA_CANINIA_BODY}					The Roman Senate have passed a law to deal with the problem of slaves being freed in the wills of their now-dead masters. Mass manumission is no longer allowed, and only a fraction of someone's slaves can be declared free in his will.

¬ Events for Barbarian Invasion


{NEW_TESTAMENT_FORMULATED_TITLE}						New Testament Formulated 
{THE_SASSANID_MARTYRDOM_TITLE}						The Sassanid Martyrdoms
{THE_MARTYRDOM_OF_SAINT_EUSEBIUS_TITLE}				The Martyrdom Of Saint Eusebius
{FIRST_COUNCIL_OF_CONSTANTINOPLE_TITLE}				First Council of Constantinople
{THE_SERAPEUM_DESTROYED_TITLE}						The Serapeum Destroyed
{FINAL_OLYMPIC_GAMES_HELD_TITLE}						Final Olympic Games Held
{COUNCIL_OF_CARTHAGE_TITLE}							Council of Carthage
{THE_NOTITIA_DIGNITARUM_TITLE}						The Notitia Dignitarum
{THE_VULGATE_TITLE}									The Vulgate
{HERETICAL_BRITISH_MONK_DISAPPPEARS_TITLE}			Heretical British Monk Disapppears
{PATRICK_INTRODUCES_CHRISTIANITY_TO_IRELAND_TITLE}	Patrick Introduces Christianity To Ireland
{COUNCIL_OF_EPHESUS_TITLE}							Council of Ephesus
{LEGAL_CODE_REVISED_TITLE}							Legal Code Revised
{COUNCIL_OF_CHALCEDON_TITLE}							Council of Chalcedon
{PAPAL_PRIMACY_TITLE}									Papal Primacy
{THE_SLAVS_EMERGE_TITLE}								The Slavs Emerge
{PAGAN_PHILOSOPHER_MURDERED_TITLE}					Pagan Philosopher Murdered

{NEW_TESTAMENT_FORMULATED_BODY}						Athanasius has finished collating his New Testament, presenting the canon in a twenty-seven book form (the omitted books become known as the Apocrypha). There are whispers that the decision as to what to include and what to omit had more to do with the political interests of Church leaders than true doctrine.
{THE_SASSANID_MARTYRDOM_BODY}							In an effort to drive Christianity out of his Armenian lands, the Sassanid ruler has martyred many Christians, including Joseph of Persia and the 80-year-old Bishop of Hnaita. It is thought that his actions are intended to taunt the Roman Empire as to its powerlessness to intervene. The men were tortured and then beaten to death.
{THE_MARTYRDOM_OF_SAINT_EUSEBIUS_BODY}				Eusebius, the Bishop of Samosata in Syria, has been martyred by a roof tile that was hurled at him during a Church ceremony. Eusebius had defied the Arian Emperor Constantius in 361 by refusing to hand over the records of the Synod of Antioch, despite the threat of losing a hand. His resolution was so impressive that Constantius let him go unharmed.
{FIRST_COUNCIL_OF_CONSTANTINOPLE_BODY}				The Christian Church has held a Council in Constantinople to mark the final defeat of Arianism, the heretical teachings of Arius, the third century mystic. All his books were ordered destroyed and Arianism was made a crime in 326, but his teachings about the nature of Christ were appealing to many, including the Goths. Now, however, such wrong thinking has been entirely suppressed.
{THE_SERAPEUM_DESTROYED_BODY}							In an effort to destroy pagan influences in Alexandria, the Bishop of Alexandria has stripped the treasures from pagan temples and displayed them in his churches. In the troubles that followed the pagans barricaded themselves inside the Serapeum, a most impressive temple dedicated to the sacred bull Apis. They were given safe passage but promises to leave the temple alone were conveniently ignored when a Christian mob was allowed to tear down the structure stone by stone.
{FINAL_OLYMPIC_GAMES_HELD_BODY}						The Olympic Games, having been held every fourth year for at least a thousand years, are now at an end, as the Emperor has decreed them to be a pagan festival.
{COUNCIL_OF_CARTHAGE_BODY}							A Church Council held in the city of Carthage has extended the doctrine and practices of the Christian Church. After careful argument it has been decided firstly that prayers for the dead will have an effect in making sure that they reach Heaven; secondly, some sins can be atoned for by the dead soul spending time in Purgatory, paying off bad behaviour by suffering the torments of damnation for a given time.
{THE_NOTITIA_DIGNITARUM_BODY}							This huge list of dignitaries, the state offices they hold, and the position and composition of the armed forces is at last complete. The Notitia Dignitatum lists every government job in both halves of the Empire, and gives the authority and responsibilities of each.
{THE_VULGATE_BODY}									Jerome has completed his translation of the Old and New Testaments from Hebrew and Aramaic into Latin. This massive work - the versio vulgata, or Vulgate Bible - soon becomes the standard catholic, or universal, biblical version of the book. Unfortunately, Jerome's translation is marred in some particulars by the speed at which he worked, which resulted in errors and misconceptions.
{HERETICAL_BRITISH_MONK_DISAPPPEARS_BODY}				Pelagius, a Romano-British monk and scholar - may have been murdered because of his heretical teachings. He had made the mistake of arguing against Augustine's teachings, proposing ideas of living and sin that had much in common with pagan Stoic thought. He had also managed to avoid condemnation for heresy once, but the combined authority of Augustine and Jerome lead to his excommunication at the Council of Carthage. Shortly after his excommunication, Pelagius disappeared. Foul play has been suspected.
{PATRICK_INTRODUCES_CHRISTIANITY_TO_IRELAND_BODY}		Patricius - or Patrick - has returned to Ireland with the gospel of Christianity. Formerly a slave there until the age of 16, Maewyn Succat escaped, studied in monasteries across the mainland of Europe and changed his name to Patricius. He went back to Ireland as a result of a command that he received in a dream.
{COUNCIL_OF_EPHESUS_BODY}								A Church Council convened in Ephesus has denounced the teachings of the Christian scholar Nestorius as heretical and against the true beliefs of the Church. Nestorius had argued - a little too loudly - that Christ had completely separate human and divine aspects to his nature.
{LEGAL_CODE_REVISED_BODY}								The entire edifice of Roman law has been put on a sensible footing as all the laws, statutes and decrees from 1000 years have been organised, codified and ordered. Laws have been ordered so older laws that were superceeded are listed in date order, allowing a more sensible interpretation of the law in both halves of the Empire, and making all parts of the Roman world feel part of a greater whole.
{COUNCIL_OF_CHALCEDON_BODY}							The Ecumenical Council has met in Chalcedon and refined the Church's creed concerning the person and work of Christ by voting that, after all the arguments had been considered, he was 'truly man and truly God'. The Council also decided to raise the status of the patriarchy of Constantinople, by giving it authority over Pontus, Asia and Thrace.
{PAPAL_PRIMACY_BODY}									The Patricarch of Rome, the Pope, has declared a new doctrine that gives him absolute authority over the Christian Church. He argues that his authority is divine, directly from God even though it is exercised by man. Many outside the Pope's immediate court have expressed concerns about this move.
{THE_SLAVS_EMERGE_BODY}								A new faction has arisen in the far north. The Slavs are a tribal people who, having found new power as a unified faction, are now migrating southwards. They will almost certainly seek easy prey in the warmer climes of Europe...oh, and displace whoever happens to be living there at the time…
{PAGAN_PHILOSOPHER_MURDERED_BODY}						Hypatia of Alexandria, the Platonic philospher, mathematician and astronomer has been murdered thanks to being a pagan, too clever by half,  and a woman. Her suspected involvement in a religious dispute between the Church and government authorities in Alexandria was enough for a group of monks to beat her to death, mutilate the corpse with broken tiles, and then burn her. Hypatia's sad death marks a sea-change in religious attitudes and toleration.

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 18/04/2005 12:45:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 27/06/2005 11:59:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 08/07/2005 17:43:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 20/07/2005 12:25:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++

¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			THERE SHOULD NOW BE NO MORE CHANGES! 
¬*			SEE ROSS/LUCI/MIKE!
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 05/08/2005 16:25:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++