¬ Localisation file for transition screen quotes
¬ Lines in brackets are not to be translated



{Quote_1}
"If I abide here and play my part in the siege of Troy, then lost is my home-return, but my renown shall be imperishable; but if I return home to my dear native land, lost then is my glorious renown, yet shall my life long endure, neither shall the doom of death come soon upon me."
Achilles to Odysseus; Homer, Iliad 9.412-6
{Author_1}
Achilles to Odysseus; Homer, Iliad 9.412-6
{Quote_2}
"You shall take many cities and slay many men."
{Author_2}
The centaur Chiron to the young Achilles; Philostratus, Imagines 2.2
{Quote_3}
"Let her accept a mortal's bed, and see her son die in battle, a son who is like Ares in the strength of his hands and like lightning in the swift prime of his feet."
{Author_3}
Themis to the gods; Pindar, Isthmian 8.36-7
{Quote_4}
"Seek not in vain, Thetis, to sink the Trojan fleet: the fates forbid it, it is the sure ordinance of heaven that Europe and Asia should join in bloody conflict."
{Author_4}
Poseidon to Thetis; Statius, Achilleid 1.80
{Quote_5}
"Avenge my son, Olympian Zeus, lord of counsel; and give might to the Trojans, until the Achaeans pay him due respect, and magnify him with recompense."
{Author_5}
Thetis to Zeus; Homer, Iliad 1.508-10
{Quote_6}
"Why has he gathered and led here his host, this son of Atreus? Was it not for Helen's sake? Do they then alone of mortal men love their wives, these sons of Atreus?"
{Author_6}
Achilles; Homer, Iliad 9.338-41
{Quote_7}
"I have no wish to live unless Hector falls by my spear and dies."
{Author_7}
Achilles to Thetis; Homer, Iliad 18.82-4
{Quote_8}
"And you, Mother, as you love me, do not try to keep me from the field. You will never hold me now."
{Author_8}
Achilles to Thetis; Homer, Iliad 18.126
{Quote_9}
"Your Majesty, the gifts can wait. Produce them, if you like, at your convenience; or keep them with you. But now let us turn our thoughts to battle."
{Author_9}
Achilles to Agamemnon; Homer, Iliad 19.147-9
{Quote_10}
"From mortal sight he [Apollo] vanished into cloud, and cloaked with mist he shot a baleful shaft which leapt to Achilles' ankle..."
{Author_10}
Arctinus of Miletus, Sack of Troy 3.70
{Quote_11}
"Do not speak soothingly to me of death, Odysseus. I would choose to serve as the serf of another, rather than to be lord over all these lifeless dead."
{Author_11}
The soul of Achilles to Odysseus; Homer, Odyssey 11.488-91
{Quote_12}
"...how often I bewail my miserable father [Agamemnon], whom bloody Ares did not welcome with deadly gifts in a foreign land, but my mother and her bed fellow Aegisthus split his head with murderous axe, just as woodmen chop an oak."
{Author_12}
Electra; Sophocles, Electra 94-9
{Quote_13}
"Look to my affairs, and to the household, and to our guest from Troy."
{Author_13}
Menelaus to Helen; Ovid, Heroides 17.160
{Quote_14}
"Many a life has perished for my sake beside Scamander's stream."
{Author_14}
Helen; Euripides, Helen, 52
{Quote_15}
"You daughter of Tyndareus, you are no child of Zeus, but I say you were born of many a father, first of some evil demon, next of Envy, then of Murder and of Death, and every horror that the earth breeds."
{Author_15}
Andromache to Helen; Euripides, Trojan Women 766-9
{Quote_16}
"For very grief I fainted, cursing Helen the sister of the Dioscuri, and Paris the baleful shepherd of Ida; for it was their marriage, which was no marriage but misery sent by some demon, that robbed me of my country and drove me from my home."
{Author_16}
Trojan captives; Euripides, Hecabe 942-9
{Quote_17}
"For nothing is greater or better than this, when man and wife dwell in a home in one accord, a great grief to their foes and a joy to their friends; but they know it best themselves."
{Author_17}
Odysseus to Nausicaa; Homer, Odyssey 6.182-4
{Quote_18}
"I will not rest till I have let hell loose upon you..."
{Author_18}
Telemachus to the suitors of Penelope; Homer, Odyssey 2.317
{Quote_19}
"A tramp's life is the worst thing that anyone can come to. But exile, misfortune, and sorrow, often force a man to put up with its miseries, for his wretched stomach's sake."
{Author_19}
Odysseus to Eumaeus; Homer, Odyssey 15.344-5
{Quote_20}
"A day can press down all human things, and a day can raise them up. But the gods embrace men of sense and abhor the evil."
{Author_20}
Athena to Odysseus; Sophocles, Ajax 131-3
{Quote_21}
"Nothing could please me more than to see [Hector's] mad career cut short and have him killed on his native soil by Achaean hands."
{Author_21}
Athena to Hera; Homer, Iliad 8.358-9
{Quote_22}
"No one is free except Zeus."
{Author_22}
Cratos to Hephaestus; Aeschylus, Prometheus Bound 50
{Quote_23}
"Gone is the old prosperity, Troy is no more! Gone are the hero-sons that I bore."
{Author_23}
Hecabe; Euripides, Trojan Women 582-3
{Quote_24}
"The man who day by day lives on, escaping misery — he is happiest."
{Author_24}
Hecabe; Euripides, Hecabe 629
{Quote_25}
"Ah, Hector, you have brought utter desolation to your parents. But who will mourn you as I shall? Mine is the bitterest regret of all, because you did not die in bed and stretching out your arms to me give me some tender word that I might have treasured in my tears by night and day."
{Author_25}
Andromache to Hector's corpse; Homer, Iliad 24.742-5
{Quote_26}
"Paris, you pretty boy, you woman seducer, why were you ever born? Why weren't you killed before your wedding day?"
{Author_26}
Hector to Paris; Homer, Iliad 3.39-40
{Quote_27}
"Come, let us go to bed together and be happy in our love."
{Author_27}
Paris to Helen; Homer, Iliad 3.440
{Quote_28}
"Give way! Do not aspire to be the equal of the gods. The immortals are not made of the same stuff as men that walk on the ground!"
{Author_28}
Apollo to Diomedes; Homer, Iliad 5.440-2
{Quote_29}
"I wish that I could sink my teeth into that man's very liver and eat it!"
{Author_29}
Hecabe on Achilles; Homer, Iliad 24.212-4
{Quote_30}
"We did not come from Argos to give special terms to Troy, but to fight you to the death. Therefore, if you are still desirous of war, the Achaeans are ready..."
{Author_30}
Diomedes to the Trojan council; Dictys 5.6
{Quote_31}
"Of all the cities that men live under the sun and the starry sky, the nearest to my heart was Troy, with Priam and the people of Priam."
{Author_31}
Zeus to Hera; Homer, Iliad 4.44-7
{Quote_32}
"I have endured what no other mortal on the face of earth has yet endured, to reach forth my hand to the face of him that has slain my sons."
{Author_32}
Priam to Achilles; Homer, Iliad 24.504-6
{Quote_33}
"Take the reins and rule your state, sitting on your father's throne, but wield the sceptre with better faith."
{Author_33}
Heracles to Priam; Seneca, Trojan Women 718-9
{Quote_34}
"Who could blame the Trojans and Achaeans for suffering so long for such a woman's sake? Indeed she is the very image of an immortal goddess."
{Author_34}
Trojan elders; Homer, Iliad 3.156-7
{Quote_35}
"I beg you, my dear son, not to stand up against Achilles alone and unsupported..."
{Author_35}
Priam to Hector; Homer, Iliad 22.40
{Quote_36}
"Son of Achilles, slay me, and pity not my misery. I have no will to see the sun's light more."
{Author_36}
Priam to Neoptolemus; Quintus Smyrnaeus, Fall of Troy 13.225
{Quote_37}
"Learn courage from me, and true toil; from others the meaning of fortune."
{Author_37}
Aeneas to his son Ascanius; Virgil, Aeneid 12.435-6
{Quote_38}
"Even Zeus might be angry if Achilles killed Aeneas, who after all is destined to survive and to save the House of Dardanus from extinction."
{Author_38}
Poseidon to the gods; Homer, Iliad 20.301-5
{Quote_39}
"Trojans, trust not the horse. Whatever it be, I fear the Greeks, even when bringing gifts."
{Author_39}
Laocoon to the Trojans; Virgil, Aeneid 2.48-9
{Quote_40}
"We praise not Hector; though his name, we know, is great in arms; 'tis hard to praise a foe."
{Author_40}
Nestor; Ovid, Metamorphoses 12.550-1
{Quote_41}
"Hector is going to give his enemies no rest until Achilles comes to life again beside his ships on the day when at the sterns of the ships they shall be fighting about Patroclus fallen. That is decreed by Heaven."
{Author_41}
Zeus to Hera; Homer, Iliad 8.473-7
{Quote_42}
"Agamemnon has built a wall and dug a trench along it, complete with palisade. But even so he cannot keep the murderous Hector out!"
{Author_42}
Achilles to Odysseus; Homer, Iliad 9.349-52
{Quote_43}
"You too, I swear it, have not long to live. Already Destiny and Death are very close to you, and you will die at the hands of Achilles."
{Author_43}
Patroclus to Hector; Homer, Iliad 16.852-4
{Quote_44}
"I am going to meet Achilles, though his hands are like fire, and his heart like steel."
{Author_44}
Hector; Homer, Iliad 20.371-2
{Quote_45}
"Your heart is hard as iron. Nevertheless, pause before you act, in case the angry gods remember how you treated me, when your turn comes and you are killed at the Scaean Gate by Paris and Apollo."
{Author_45}
Hector to Achilles; Homer, Iliad 22.357-60
{Quote_46}
"I see even now a city destined to the descendants of the Phrygians, than which none greater is or shall be, or has been in past ages."
{Author_46}
Helenus to Aeneas; Ovid, Metamorphoses 15.444-5
{Quote_47}
"I, too, in my youth once had a slow tongue and an active hand. But now I see that the tongue, not action, is what masters everything among men."
{Author_47}
Odysseus to Neoptolemus; Sophocles, Philoctetes 92
{Quote_48}
"Father, with the help of the gods even a worthless man might achieve victory; but I, even without that help, fully trust to bring that glory within my grasp."
{Author_48}
Ajax to Telamon; Sophocles, Ajax 767-9
{Quote_49}
"Let us exchange our armour, so that everyone may know that our grandfathers' friendship has made friends of us."
{Author_49}
Diomedes to Glaucus; Homer, Iliad 6.230-1
{Quote_50}
"Daughter of Nereus, you shall bear a son, a dazzling light to Thessaly... for he shall come with an army of Myrmidon spearmen to the famous land of Priam, to set it in a blaze..."
{Author_50}
Chiron to Thetis; Euripides, Iphigenia in Aulis 1062-70
{Quote_51}
"Never be too gentle with your wife, nor show her all that is in your mind."
{Author_51}
The ghost of Agamemnon to Odysseus; Homer, Odyssey 11.441-2
{Quote_52}
"Olympus is the abode of the gods that stands fast forever. Neither is it shaken by winds nor ever wet with rain, nor does snow fall upon it, but the air is outspread clear and cloudless, and over it hovers a radiant whiteness. Therein the blessed gods are glad all their days..."
{Author_52}
Athena; Homer, Odyssey 6.42-6
{Quote_53}
"The legends of Greece generally have different forms, and this is particularly true of genealogy."
{Author_53}
Pausanias, Guide to Greece 8.53.5
{Quote_54}
"A strangely potent tie is kinship, and companionship as well."
{Author_54}
Hephaestus; Aeschylus, Prometheus Bound 39
{Quote_55}
"There are no pacts between lions and men: wolves and lambs are never of one accord, but are fixed in hatred of each other for all time."
{Author_55}
Achilles to Hector; Homer, Iliad 22.262-4
{Quote_56}
"Most hateful to me are you of all gods on Olympus, for ever is strife dear to you and wars and fightings."
{Author_56}
Zeus to Ares; Homer, Iliad 5.890-1
{Quote_57}
"Do you know that only the other day that pestilential, double-dealing villain gave Hera and myself his word to fight against the Trojans and help the Argives? And now he has forgotten all he said and is fighting on the Trojan side."
{Author_57}
Athena on Ares; Homer, Iliad 5.831-4
{Quote_58}
"Do you not see how mighty is the goddess Aphrodite? She sows and gives that love from which all we upon this earth are born."
{Author_58}
Nurse of Phaedra; Euripides, Hippolytus 450-1
{Quote_59}
"Forbear against Aeneas' noble head to hurl the bitter dart, the deadly spear! Fated he is by the high Gods' decree to pass from Xanthus, and by Tiber's flood to found a city holy and glorious."
{Author_59}
Calchas to the Achaeans; Quintus Smyrnaeus, The Fall of Troy 13.335-7
{Quote_60}
"As for my own self, let me live long and happily, seeing the light of the sun, and come to the threshold of Old Age, a man prosperous among the people."
{Author_60}
Homeric Hymn to Aphrodite 5.105-7
{Quote_61}
"Goddess, sing of the wrath of Peleus' son Achilles, murderous, doomed, that cost the Achaeans countless losses hurling down to the House of Death so many sturdy souls, great fighters' souls..."
{Author_61}
Homer, Iliad 1.1-4
{Quote_62}
"Hades is not to be soothed, neither overcome, wherefore he is most hated by mortals of all gods."
{Author_62}
Agamemnon; Homer, Iliad 9.158-9
{Quote_63}
"Mycenae, the leader of the Greeks in the Trojan war, and Nineveh, where was the royal palace of the Assyrians, are utterly ruined and desolate... The case of Tiryns in the Argolid is the same. These places have been reduced by heaven to nothing."
{Author_63}
Pausanias, Guide to Greece 8.33.2
{Quote_64}
"Wealth is most valued by men, and of all things in the world it has the greatest power. This I have come to secure at the head of my great army; for a man well-born but poor is worth nothing."
{Author_64}
Polynices; Euripides, Phoenician Women 439-42
{Quote_65}
"Many are the homes and cities once prosperous that Ambition has entered and left, to the ruin of her worshippers."
{Author_65}
Iocasta; Euripides, Phoenician Women 533-4
{Quote_66}
"Swift is the achievement, short are the ways of gods, when bent on speed."
{Author_66}
Pindar, Pythian 9.68
{Quote_67}
"On kings and captains weigh many a care."
{Author_67}
Agamemnon to Iphigenia; Euripides, Iphigenia in Aulis 645
{Quote_68}
"To gaze upon the light is man's most cherished gift; that life below is nothingness, and whoever longs for death is mad. Better live a life of woe than die a death of glory!"
{Author_68}
Iphigenia to Agamemnon; Euripides, Iphigenia in Aulis 1250-3
{Quote_69}
"Gods manifest themselves in many forms, bring many matters to surprising ends: the things we thought would happen do not happen, the unexpected God makes possible."
{Author_69}
Women of Phthia; Euripides, Andromache 1284-5
{Quote_70}
"You coward! Did you once command an army? Yes, to win a woman; not to help your friends."
{Author_70}
Orestes to Menelaus; Euripides, Orestes 718-9
{Quote_71}
"I sing of arms and a man..."
{Author_71}
Virgil, Aeneid 1.1
{Quote_72}
"We Cyclopes do not concern ourselves over Zeus... nor any of the rest of the blessed gods, since we are far better than they."
{Author_72}
The Cyclops Polyphemus to Odysseus; Homer, Odyssey 9.275-6
{Quote_73}
"Cyclops, if anyone ever asks you how you came by your unsightly blindness, tell him your eye was put out by Odysseus, Sacker of Cities, the son of Laertes, who lives in Ithaca."
{Author_73}
Odysseus to the Cyclops Polyphemus; Homer, Odyssey 9.502-5
{Quote_74}
"Discord strides exulting in her torn mantle, followed by Bellona wielding a bloodstained scourge."
{Author_74}
Virgil, Aeneid 7.702-3
{Quote_75}
"Discord is the last of the gods to close an argument."
{Author_75}
Antigone to a herald; Aeschylus, Seven Against Thebes 1057
{Quote_76}
"Truly Discord is a goddess to fear."
{Author_76}
Euripides, Phoenician Women 799
{Quote_77}
"Menelaus, know that the gods made wine the best thing for mortal man to scatter cares."
{Author_77}
Cypria fr. 13 (Athenaeus 13C)
{Quote_78}
"Where fear is, there too is shame."
{Author_78}
Cypria fr. 20 (Plato, Euthyphro 12A)
{Quote_79}
"Zeus... resolved to relieve the all-nurturing earth of men by causing the great struggle of the Ilian war, that the load of death might empty the world. And so the heroes were slain in Troy, and the plan of Zeus came to pass."
{Author_79}
Cypria fr. 3 (Scholiast on Homer, Iliad 1.5)
{Quote_80}
"Gifts beguile men's minds and their deeds as well."
{Author_80}
Returns fr. 5 (Clement of Alexandria, Strom., vi. 2. 12. 8)
{Quote_81}
"I sing of Ilium and Dardania, the land of fine horses, wherein the Danaans, followers of Ares, suffered many things."
{Author_81}
Little Iliad fr. 2 (Ps. Herodotus, Life of Homer)
{Quote_82}
"Even a woman could carry a load once a man had put it on her shoulder; but she could not fight. For she would fail with fear if she should fight."
{Author_82}
Little Iliad fr. 3 (Scholiast on Aristophanes, Knights 1056)
{Quote_83}
"When he had fallen, bloody death and hard fate seized on Astyanax. And Neoptolemus chose out Andromache, Hector's well-girded wife, and the chiefs of all the Achaeans gave her to him to hold requiting him with a welcome prize."
{Author_83}
Little Iliad fr. 13 (Scholiast on Lycophron Alex., 1268)
{Quote_84}
"If Priam's city be doomed indeed, and by guile must fall before the war-worn Achaeans, let us make a great horse, in which our mightiest will lay in ambush."
{Author_84}
Odysseus to the Achaeans; Quintus Smyrnaeus, Fall of Troy 12.25
{Quote_85}
"Wife, one thing is certain—not all our soldiers will return from Troy unhurt."
{Author_85}
Odysseus to Penelope; Homer, Odyssey 18.260
{Quote_86}
"Now there is nobody who will escape death when god puts him into my hands in front of Troy, none among all the Trojans, and above all none of the sons of Priam."
{Author_86}
Achilles to Lycaon; Homer, Iliad 21.102-5
{Quote_87}
"Before the pursuit of Achilles the roaring stream of deep-swirling Xanthus was filled with a mingled mass of men and horses."
{Author_87}
Homer, Iliad 21.15-6
{Quote_88}
"Achilles jumped out of the whirling water and, terrified, made a dash to go flying across the plain with all the speed of his legs."
{Author_88}
Homer, Iliad 21.246-8
{Quote_89}
"The lyre and the curved bow shall ever be dear to me, and I will declare to men the unfailing will of Zeus."
{Author_89}
Apollo; Homeric Hymn to Apollo 131
{Quote_90}
"There are two jars standing on Zeus' floor which hold the gifts he gives us: one holds evils, the other blessings."
{Author_90}
Achilles to Priam; Homer, Iliad 24.527-8
{Quote_91}
"Now Mycenae may have been a small place, and many of the towns of that age may appear comparatively insignificant, but no exact observer would therefore feel justified in rejecting the estimate given by the poets and by tradition of the magnitude of the armament."
{Author_91}
Thucydides 1.10.1
{Quote_92}
"And the first person known to us by tradition as having established a navy is Minos. He made himself master of what is now called the Hellenic sea, and ruled over the Cyclades, into most of which he sent the first colonies, expelling the Carians and appointing his own sons governors."
{Author_92}
Thucydides 1.8.2
{Quote_93}
"We of Asia did not deign to notice the seizure of our women; but the Greeks, for the sake of a Lacedaemonian woman, recruited a great armada, came to Asia, and destroyed the power of Priam. Ever since then we have regarded Greeks as our enemies."
{Author_93}
'What the Persians say'; Herodotus 1.4.3-4
{Quote_94}
"Had Helen been Priam's own wife, I cannot but think that he would have restored her to the Greeks, if by so doing he could escape from the evils besetting him."
{Author_94}
Herodotus 2.120.3
{Quote_95}
"Nestor will not utter a lie, for he is wise indeed."
{Author_95}
Athena; Homer, Odyssey 3.20
{Quote_96}
"As a general thing we find that the ancient myths do not give us a simple and consistent story... in some details they are not in agreement with those given by every poet and historian."
{Author_96}
Diodorus Siculus, Library of History 4.44.5
{Quote_97}
"Here was Minos, a man who exceeded all men in cruelty, and who enslaved with his navies the inhabitants of continent and islands alike..."
{Author_97}
Philostratus, Life of Apollonius of Tyana 3.25
{Quote_98}
"Many a life beside Scamander's streams perished for me."
{Author_98}
Helen; Euripides, Helen 52
{Quote_99}
"This thought occurred to Tyndareus: the suitors should swear to each other and join right hands and pour libations with burnt-sacrifice..."
{Author_99}
Agamemnon; Euripides, Iphigenia in Aulis 57f.
{Quote_100}
"Away with you, base children that are my shame; would that you all together in Hector's stead had been slain…!"
{Author_100}
Priam to his sons; Homer, Iliad 24.254







¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 06/02/2006 14:15
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++



¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 14/02/2006 11:00
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++


¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*
¬*			CHANGES BENEATH THIS LINE!!!
¬*		
¬*
¬*			Only changes made after 27/02/2006 17:30
¬*
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬*******************************************************************************************************
¬+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++




































