"There was a time when the countless tribes of men, though wide-dispersed, oppressed the surface of the deep-bosomed earth, and Zeus saw it and had pity, and in his wise heart resolved to relieve the all-nurturing earth of men by causing the great struggle of the Trojan War, that the load of death might empty the world. And so the heroes were slain in Troy, and the plan of Zeus came to pass."
Cypria fr. 3 (Schol. Hom. Il. 1.5)

At first the cruel goddess Discord, barred from the wedding feast of Peleus and Thetis, jealously threw an apple among the assembled guests inscribed with these words: "For the fairest". The goddesses Athena, Aphrodite and Hera began to argue bitterly over who should receive the apple, though this was merely the first conflict in a deadly chain of events that would bring Zeus' plan to pass: he would relieve the toils of the earth by leading the heroes to kill one another in the Trojan War. Since that time, the goddesses chose the Trojan prince Paris to judge which of the three was the fairest; Paris selected Aphrodite, and in return received Helen, the most beautiful woman in the world, as his reward. He stole her away from her husband Menelaus and brought her to the city of Troy.

Now Menelaus and his brother Agamemnon have gathered a great host of the bronze-greaved Achaeans, invoking the Oath of Tyndareus, and have sailed across the expanse of Minos' sea to wage war on the horse-taming Trojans. The Achaean army has subdued the islands off the Trojan coast, and are poised to do battle with their enemy around the walls of Troy herself. The walls of Troy are strong, however, and the Achaeans will not be able to take the city straight away. Moreover, the Achaean army is large, and the sons of Atreus will need to capture many surrounding cities in order to gain the supplies and gold necessary to keep their warriors in the field in the long term. The Trojans, for their part, were not prepared for this war, and must rapidly assemble their forces and allies from surrounding cities in order to fend off their powerful attackers, in order to take the initiative from the Achaean armies.

The 'Cypria' was a long narrative poem, like the Iliad, in the 'Epic Cycle' of poems about the Trojan War. While the Iliad narrates a few select days towards the end of the war, the Cypria tells the story of the Trojan War right from the beginning, with Zeus' decision that the earth was overpopulated and that a large section of the human race must be exterminated. It continues to describe how the war itself developed out of a series of events that rapidly spiral out of both human and divine control, and then narrates the course of the war up until the point at which the Iliad begins. Scholars generally agree that the Cypria was composed after the Iliad, since it forms what seems to be a deliberate 'prequel' to Homer's great work. Evidently, like the majority of the other poems in the Epic Cycle, the Cypria was not considered to be of the same quality as the Iliad, since no complete version of the poem has managed to survive down to the present day. Instead, we only know about the poem because ancient Greek scholars - often in the course of providing commentaries to the Iliad - have provided summaries of it and occasionally quotations as well. Regarding the overall storyline, we derive almost everything we know from a work called the 'Chrestomathy' ('Lessons for a Gentleman') by an otherwise unknown grammarian called 'Proclus', who probably lived after Christ. For scholars such as Proclus, the study of ancient poems like the Cypria and the Iliad would have been akin to the study of Chaucer or Shakespeare by modern scholars.

The Cypria itself was possibly composed in the later 7th century BC, and is often attributed by ancient scholars to one Stasinus of Cyprus (hence the name 'Cypria', which is otherwise inexplicable). Another story is that it was Homer who composed the poem, but gave it to Stasinus as a dowry. Others have claimed that it was composed by one Hegesias/Hegesinus of Cyprus, or by one Cyprias of Halicarnassus. The problem will most likely never be resolved.