"There are no pacts between lions and men: wolves and lambs are never of one accord, but are fixed in hatred of each other for all time."
- Hom. Il. 22.262-4

The war has dragged on longer than any other war in the memory of man. Battle has followed battle, slaughter has followed slaughter. Many brave heroes have gone to their doom; many other heroes will be following them soon. The Achaeans have clashed many times with the Trojans and have sacked many of their cities, campaigning to and fro across Mysia and Thrace in their desperate attempt to sap Trojan strength and keep their own armies fed. The Trojans are weak now, much weaker than before, but their mighty walls still hold strong. The Achaeans too have grown weaker, and their armies are becoming restless and perhaps even mutinous. To cap it all, Achilles, the greatest of the Achaean heroes, has been slighted by King Agamemnon and has withdrawn indefinitely from the fighting. The Achaeans had just returned from the sacking of the town of Thebe, and each had taken his own prize of honour from that city. Agamemnon had the girl Chryseis, daughter of Chryses, priest of Apollo. However, Apollo then sent a plague to the Achaeans, and Agamemnon has been forced to give the girl back to her father. Not to be left in dishonour, Agamemnon has chosen to take Achilles' prize, a girl named Briseis, instead.

And so it is that Achilles has withdrawn from the war and refuses, for the time being, to set foot outside his camp. Moreover, his mother Thetis has appealed to Zeus to give victory to the Trojans in the meantime, so that the Achaeans may feel the want of Achilles' help and may go back to him in grovelling supplication. Without Achilles' help, will the Achaeans be able to withstand the Trojan counterattack, led by their prince Hector? On the other hand, do the Trojans truly have enough men and resources to force the Achaeans out of Mysia? They will need to recapture many of their lost towns in order to regain their strength and win a decisive victory over their opponents. One thing is certain: only the dead have seen the end of the war.

The Iliad is, without a doubt, the most famous poem in Western civilisation, and is rightly hailed as a masterpiece of narrative art. The poem tells the story of just a few days in the tenth year of the war, beginning with Apollo sending the plague on behalf of Chryses. It goes on to describe the wrath of Achilles, dishonoured by Agamemnon, and the subsequent Trojan onslaught led by Hector. Thanks to Zeus, the Trojans are extremely successful for a time, until finally Achilles agrees to allow his close friend and companion Patroclus to go out and fight the Trojan prince. Patroclus is slain, and so Achilles redoubles his rage and redirects it from Agamemnon to Hector and the Trojans. At last Achilles and Hector face one another in a climactic duel, and Hector is killed. King Priam then pays Achilles a personal visit and, in a deeply moving scene, Achilles realises the futility of his anger and feels sympathy for Priam, realising that the old king is just like his own father, and he is just like Hector. For mortals all face the same hardships and suffering in life, regardless of whether they are friends or enemies, and it is only the gods who may live free of care. The poem ends with the funeral of Hector, symbolising the capture of Troy which now seems inevitable. 